<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[Youri in Japan]]></title><description><![CDATA[My experiences in Japan during the Vulcanus in Japan 2016-2017 exchange program]]></description><link>http://youri.discovers.asia</link><image><url>images/landscape_japan.svg</url><title>Youri in Japan</title><link>http://youri.discovers.asia</link></image><generator>RSS for Node</generator><lastBuildDate>Sun, 09 Oct 2016 09:39:38 GMT</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://youri.discovers.asia/rss/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><ttl>60</ttl><item><title><![CDATA[What I like about Japan]]></title><description><![CDATA[<div id="preamble">
<div class="sectionbody">
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Being in Japan for already 40 days, I noticed a lot of stuff that makes my life pleasant. I&#8217;ll try to give a summary of some of the positive things I encountered so far. First, I also wanted to summarize the stuff I don&#8217;t like about Japan so far (and yes, there are some points you won&#8217;t like about any country), but I&#8217;ll keep that for another post, so stay tuned!</p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_public_transport">Public transport</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Most of you know the legends and fairy tales about perfect train systems on which the train never comes late: the tales are true, my friend! This is absolutely the greatest thing I have encountered so far. Being used to public transport in Belgium, especially busses, Japanese public transport is a relief! Trains arrive and leave ON TIME, and then I mean SPOT-ON! In Belgium, you have to be happy if your train only arrives 5 minutes late, which is still considered on time by the NMBS (the Belgian rail company).</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>I commute between the stations Musashi-Kosugi (near my apartment) and Shibuya (near to my school) and can choose between 3 different kinds of trains on my line: Local, Express and Commuter Express. Local trains stop at every station on the line and hence are the slowest ones. Shibuya is the first station on the line and Musashi-Kosugi the eleventh, so 10 stops until I reach my destination, which takes about half an hour. The Express train skips 3 to 4 stations, but the fastest trains on the line are the Commuter Express trains. These only stop at the greater stations where you can transfer to another line. Now of course, everyone is keen on commuting quicker, which means that a lot of people prefer the Commuter Express, especially in the morning when people have to get to work or school in time. Result: whenever I tried to take the Commuter Express in the mornings, I was literally being a sardine in a can. (Could I get some lemon and salt with that?) So I prefer taking the local train instead, which will also be crowded in the mornings, but at least you can move your arms to catch your phone and read a newspaper. Commuting time doesn&#8217;t differ that much after all in my case. I guess I can gain only 10 minutes in the morning and since I leave pretty early to school, it doesn&#8217;t really matter to me. However, in the early afternoon (let&#8217;s say 15:00) the Commuter Express really gives a benefit. Then, it only takes me 10 to 12 minutes to commute between my stations and you can sit comfortably too since it isn&#8217;t that crowded.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Next to this, there are general habits in train stations that make life easier and bearable for everyone: queueing. <strong><em>What do you mean? People actually properly stand in lines to enter the train? Can people actually behave civilized?</em></strong> EXACTLY, no fighting to get in or out of the train, people properly wait until it is their turn to get in. And not only for entering the train! In huge stations, like Shibuya, you have thousands of people transferring and commuting. Therefore, a dozen of train lines enter this station, making it a huge maze, with several floors. Having so much floors in your station means you definitely have to use escalators to get around. In Japan, there is the nice habit to keep one half of the escalator free for people who are in a hurry and therefore want to walk/run on the escalators. Of course, before you get on the escalator, you queue properly in the correct line: the line for people that run on the escalators, or the line for people that stand still on the escalator.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>And then finally the last but certainly not the least thing I like about Japanese public transport: navigation. Having huge stations means you can easily get lost. However, the signs come to a help. The stations are filled with them. And luckily: all these signs have English translations! As a foreigner this is really a relief.  You simply follow the arrows to the line or exit you want to reach and done.</p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_general_kindness">General kindness</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Whenever you enter a store, you will be greeted by most of the staff. Their smiles and bows bring you in a really happy mood. But this kindness is not only present in stores, in the stations you have the common habit not to bother each other on the trains and queue properly for escalators and entering the train wagon. Japan has a huge population, especially in Tokyo, so you have to cope with the fact that there are a lot of people around you. When you want to feel at ease, you should ensure that you let others feel at ease. The best way to deal with each other is being calm and polite. But of course, this has to come from both sides! Don&#8217;t be rude, nor stare at people! Offer your seat for the elderly! Don&#8217;t, but really, DON&#8217;T play music aloud on the train! There are headsets, so use them! Turn the ringtone of your mobile phone off.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>People also help you whenever you ask them to! Let me give you an anecdote to illustrate this: last week, I was at a おこのみやき (okonomiyaki) restaurant with the other Fujitsu boys and wanted to order a new dish that we hadn&#8217;t tried before: もんじゃやき (monjayaki). Normally, you grill/cook the dish yourself at your table, but we had no clue how to do this properly since it wasn&#8217;t exactly the same as the okonomiyaki we were used to. So we asked the waiter how to do this and he grilled it for us! He really took effort in showing it to us instead of just explaining it briefly, which I really appreciate.</p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_public_bathrooms_are_free_clean">Public bathrooms are free &amp; CLEAN</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<div class="paragraph">
<p>In Belgium, you easily pay 50 cents of 'maintenance fee' to use a public toilet and from time to time these bathrooms have a rather 'used' impression. But people in Japan have a better understanding of general hygiene in my opinion and leave the toilets behind in the way they want to encounter them: clean. So no need to pay a toilet lady that has to supervise the bathroom continuously and clean the place. Of course these toilets get properly cleaned, but at least in Japan the staff does not have to be present all the time to check whether you aim correctly or not.</p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_convenience_stores_convenience_stores_everywhere">Convenience stores, convenience stores everywhere</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<div class="paragraph">
<p>コンビニ (konbini, short for convenience store) are everywhere. For the Belgian reader, you can compare these shops to Carrefour Express or City Delhaize. Just across my apartment, there is a 7-Eleven, where I can buy warm bento&#8217;s whenever I don&#8217;t want to go out for dinner (At the moment I don&#8217;t cook myself but I&#8217;m planning to!). Next to this, these stores are 24/7 open! How べんり　(benri: convenient) is that? The prices are bit more expensive than in the supermarket, but people gladly pay a bit more for the convenience. Next to buying food, I can also withdraw cash from the ATM over there.</p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_food_establishments_at_fair_prices">Food establishments at fair prices</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<div class="paragraph">
<p>There&#8217;s no need to cook for yourself if you don&#8217;t want to. There are tons of places you can go to have lunch or dinner. Going out for food is quite common here, and therefore it doesn&#8217;t have to be expensive at all! You&#8217;d guess of course you can only get junk food at low prices but less is true. You have a lot of simple dishes that can be bought that aren&#8217;t that fat. The greatest example might be ラーメン (raamen: noodle soup) which is cheap and you feel satisfied and full after one bowl. As a person who has always struggled with his weight, I can say that I managed to keep my weight stable until now!</p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="__">百円ストアー</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<div class="paragraph">
<p>In Europe we have a similar thing, a 1 euro store, but what you often find in such stores is mostly rubbish. However in a 百円ストアー (hyaku-en stoa, 100 yen store) you find a lot of simple necessities that make your daily life easier: chopsticks, cups, glasses, plates, knifes, paper, pencils&#8230;&#8203; you find a lot of stuff at very low prices. Most of the stuff costs 100 yen (which is currently around 86 eurocents if I recall correctly), but whenever it is more expensive, it is notified on the product. However, don&#8217;t forget you pay 8% of taxes on your products, so you actually pay 108 yen for the product if it&#8217;s labeled to be 100 yen!</p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_crazy_food_combinations">Crazy food combinations</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Ever considered eating chips with honey? Or what did you think of mayonnaise on your omelet? Ketchup on your rice?! For me, it sounded really strange and disgusting, but I was wrong. Being in a new country means you will get to know new types of food and habits that you&#8217;re not used to, which is why I was really surprised by some food combinations they make in Japan, but certainly in a positive way. It&#8217;s really good! Ever considered pouring warm egg yolk (the yellow part of an egg) over your rice? You should give it a try!</p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_supermarkets_are_open_until_22_00">Supermarkets are open until 22:00</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<div class="paragraph">
<p>That&#8217;s quite late in comparison to Belgium, where the supermarkets close at 20:00 (except for 21:00 on Fridays). And you know what&#8217;s even better? The hour before they close, they give discounts to all the fresh food that&#8217;s still available and otherwise has to be thrown away! Also the supermarkets are open on every day. Even on Sundays! I weekly visit the supermarket before closing time to buy some milk, cereal and some other drinks in big bottles. But I also check whether there is a bento or some other dish that I can take along as late night dinner at 50% of the price.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Guess I&#8217;ll stop this post for now. Next time, I&#8217;ll try to introduce my school life in Shibuya. Hope you still enjoy my blog! Stay tuned!</p>
</div>
</div>
</div>]]></description><link>http://youri.discovers.asia/2016/10/09/What-I-like-about-Japan.html</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://youri.discovers.asia/2016/10/09/What-I-like-about-Japan.html</guid><pubDate>Sun, 09 Oct 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Settling in Japan]]></title><description><![CDATA[<div id="preamble">
<div class="sectionbody">
<div class="paragraph">
<p>I know it has been a while since my previous post. My apologies for my procrastination: ごめんね (gomenne: my apologies)! It&#8217;s already been a month since I touched Japanese soil for the first time, unimaginable! Time flies, it feels as if I&#8217;ve been here only 2 weeks. Anyway, I&#8217;ll finally tell some stuff that some people have been asking me for, so here we go! Let&#8217;s talk about the "struggles" I encountered in order to ensure my journey to Japan and the measures I had to take during my first days in the country in order to settle myself in the country.</p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_before_departure">Before departure</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<div class="paragraph">
<p>On the 30th of August, I left my home country to live for a whole year in Japan for the Vulcanus in Japan exchange program. Due to the duration of the program, I couldn&#8217;t simply book my flight and jump on the plane. Some paperwork had to be done before even considering booking my flight. I am obviously talking about getting a visa. As a Belgian tourist, you don&#8217;t need to do this as long as you can prove to the Japanese immigration officer at the airport that you leave Japan within 3 months, by showing your return flight ticket.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>In order to get a visa, you first of all have to get an international passport (or travel passport, whichever one sounds good for you). This is mostly acquired by queueing a long time at your town&#8217;s civil affairs department. In Belgium, you pay a minimum of €64 for a 32-page booklet, exclusive taxes. The taxes you pay depend on the city you live in. I had the luck to live in the city with the second most expensive city taxes of Belgium, hoozaah! In total, I had to pay the generous sum of €100 to get that passport set and done.
When finally acquired your passport, you&#8217;re ready to get that visa right? Well, you can sprint to the Japanese embassee in your country and apply for a visa, but the procedure will take months and the chances of being approved are low, unless you take a detour. That detour is acquiring a Certificate of Eligibility (COE for short). The COE is a document handed out by the Japanese Ministry of Foreign Affairs to approve your long visit to Japan. I won&#8217;t go into details on how you fill in the application form, but most important in order to get such a COE is having contacts in Japan.  For students, this is often the university where they will study and for employees this is often the company that hired them.　In my case, the contact was the EU-Japan Centre for Industrial Cooperation that organises the exchange program. I received my COE during the Vulcanus Preparatory Meeting in Brussels on the 7th of July.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>With your passport and COE in your hands, you&#8217;re finally ready to hop to the Japanese embasee and apply for a visa! The procedure took around a week and the result was a beautiful sticker in my passport that grants me entry to the Land of the Rising Sun, the glorious 日本 (Nihon/Nippon: Japan). The purpose of my visa mentions "cultural activities", since the exchange program I undergo is not related to an educational institute, nor am I an employee at a particular country, which means I didn&#8217;t get a student visa nor a trainee visa. I&#8217;m a mixture of both in some way.</p>
</div>
<div id="img-visa" class="imageblock">
<div class="content">
<img src="http://youri.discovers.asia/images/settling/visa.jpg" alt="visa">
</div>
<div class="title">Figure 1. Look at this prety sticker, it has flowers and stuff written on it!</div>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>For my flight, I chose to leave from Schiphol, the international airport of The Netherlands. During the period I wanted to book my flight, there were regular strikes and delays at the Belgian airport due to the recent terrorist attacks. Therefore, I wanted to choose an airport with more stability. Gautier, the lone French Vulcanus trainee who had an intership in Amsterdam back then, was also planning to leave from Schiphol. Therefore we booked tickets for the same flight and reserved seats next to each other. The day of the flight was one full of nerves and excitement. I checked my luggage 3 times, just to be sure I would take everything I&#8217;d need with me! I arrived at the airport 3 hours before departure, so I could go tranquilly to my gate without any issues. The plane I was going to board was already waiting for me.</p>
</div>
<div id="img-plane" class="imageblock">
<div class="content">
<img src="http://youri.discovers.asia/images/settling/plane.jpg" alt="Qatar">
</div>
<div class="title">Figure 2. This plane brought me to Qatar</div>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>First, Gautier and I flew to Qatar, where we had to transfer for our flight to Narita International Airport. In Qatar, we had to sprint since we only had an hour of transfer time and we needed to go through security checks a second time and queuing took a while. We got on time in our plane, so the real trip to Japan could start! I slept a couple of hours in this plane, so the 10-hour trip didn&#8217;t feel this long luckily! When I woke up we were already flying over China. Two hours later, we were flying over Japanese soil. With a setting sun at the horizon, I was welcomed by Mount Fuji during the landing. This was for me a sign of the start of an incredible experience!</p>
</div>
<div id="img-fuji" class="imageblock">
<div class="content">
<img src="http://youri.discovers.asia/images/settling/fuji.jpg" alt="Fuji">
</div>
<div class="title">Figure 3. This is how I was welcomed into Japan</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_congratulations_you_made_it_to_japan_now_what">Congratulations, you made it to Japan! Now what?</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<div class="sect2">
<h3 id="_get_a_residence_card">Get a Residence Card</h3>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>After being landed in Narita Airport, I had to queue for passport control. During queuing I got an officer asking me the duration of my stay. The officer guided me out of the queue to some seats to wait a bit. Since I stay for more than 3 months, I had to receive a Residence Card. This card is the ID-card for foreigners who reside in Japan. This took a while and then I had a small interview with an immigration inspector and got my face photographed and fingerprints scanned, which is part of the standard procedure.</p>
</div>
<div id="img-residence" class="imageblock">
<div class="content">
<img src="http://youri.discovers.asia/images/settling/residence.jpg" alt="residence">
</div>
<div class="title">Figure 4. Ooooh shinyyy</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect2">
<h3 id="_register_your_address_and_apply_for_national_health_insurance">Register your address and apply for National Health Insurance</h3>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>The first night, I stayed in a hotel together with the other Vulcanus trainees. We got our orientation day the next morning. The Japanese weather was unforgiving: a frying 34°C and a humidity level of imeasurable values. Drenched in sweat I arrived at the Europa house, where the orientation took place. After the presentation, I had to wait for a representative of Fujitsu to pick up the students that will have their internship at Fujitsu Laboratories in Kawasaki.  In total we are 3: Sašo, from Slovenia; Ole from Germany and then there&#8217;s that Belgian guy.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>The representative brought us, after a great lunch in the most Japanese place you can imagine (read: McDonald&#8217;s), to the city hall in the Nakahara ward, where we had to register the address where we will live and had to apply for National Health Insurance. I must say this was the first time I was confronted by the known fact that nobody in Japan speaks English. The documents for address registration and insurance application were completely written in Japanese, nor could anyone of the staff assist us in English. Luckily, the Fujitsu representative stayed with us the whole afternoon to complete the forms with us. The National Health Insurance is mandatory for residents that stay at least a year in Japan. Since we only stay in Japan for a bit less than a year, the staff at the city hall wasn&#8217;t convinced we were obliged to apply for the insurance, but since we had strict orders of the EU-Japan Centre, we insisted on it and received our health insurance card. After the arrangements in the city hall were done, we had a small visit to the company where we received our appartment keys and were each guided to our appartments. Normally, we were supposed to live in the dormitory of Fujitsu, but there happened to be no vacancy left, so Fujitsu booked 3 small appartments for us. The 3 of us live apart in Leopalace21 appartments. The appartments are a small 5-minute walk from each other, so we can easily hang out together. The appartment offers more benefits for us than the dorm would have done: we all have a full private accomodation now and we can invite some visitors. Bonus!!</p>
</div>
<div id="img-nhi" class="imageblock">
<div class="content">
<img src="http://youri.discovers.asia/images/settling/nhi.jpg" alt="NHI">
</div>
<div class="title">Figure 5. My health insurance card, but some privacy bug removed my address ;)</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect2">
<h3 id="_get_a_bank_account">Get a bank account</h3>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>The next day, Friday the 2nd of September, the 3 Fujitsu guys went to Shibuya to get a bank account. We chose to go to Shinsei Bank, since they are one of the only banks that offer English services (as already mentioned, you easily get confronted with language barriers when it comes to particular domestic services). We went to the Shibuya office, but got kicked out. We were advised to go to the Head office near Tokyo Station, half an hour from Shibuya, because this office wasn&#8217;t familiar with dealing with a lot of foreigners at the same time. This was because there were already 2 Vulcanus trainees inside. The Head Office could handle us better&#8230;&#8203;</p>
</div>
<div class="admonitionblock warning">
<table>
<tr>
<td class="icon">
<i class="fa icon-warning" title="Warning"></i>
</td>
<td class="content">
<strong>Do not go in groups to a Japanese bank because the staff is not used to it and they will kick you out!</strong>
</td>
</tr>
</table>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>So we planned to go to the other office but had to do it the next week since we didn&#8217;t have anymore time that day, because a second orientation presentation was going to be held in the afternoon by the EU-Japan Centre and afterwards we were invited to a reception in the Sheraton Hotel where we had the honor to meet the principle and some members of the teaching staff from the Naganuma school. The ambassadors from some European countries and representatives from the different companies that participated in the Vulcanus program were also present. I had the opportunity to meet my supervisor for the internship, but the Belgian ambassador sent his regards. It was a very pleasant event nevertheless!</p>
</div>
<div id="img-bankcard" class="imageblock">
<div class="content">
<img src="http://youri.discovers.asia/images/settling/bankcard.jpg" alt="Shinsei">
</div>
<div class="title">Figure 6. My cash card which allows me to withdraw money from my Japanese account, but those privacy bugs removed my account number ;)</div>
</div>
<div id="img-reception" class="imageblock">
<div class="content">
<img src="http://youri.discovers.asia/images/settling/reception.jpg" alt="Reception">
</div>
<div class="title">Figure 7. This is where we held the reception, neat huh?</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect2">
<h3 id="_get_a_sim_card">Get a SIM-card</h3>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>In the first weekend, the 3 Fujitsu guys went to Shibuya again and entered a BIC CAMERA shop to get a Japanese SIM card. There are a lot of possibilities of SIM cards and plans to acquire depending on the duration of your stay and the amount of mobile data you want to consume. You can also choose whether you want a data-only SIM or would like to be able to text and make phone calls. The choice is up to you! A nice summary of the available SIM cards can be found on <a href="https://tokyocheapo.com/business/internet/prepaid-cheap-japan-sim-card-options/">Tokyo Cheapo</a> for short and long stays.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Since I stay a whole year in Japan, I chose a BIC SIM, with 3GB data per month including a phone number. Besides the initial activation costs, this will cost me 1600yen per month. Note that phone calls and text messages are excluded from this fee. So the price for the phone call you make and the numbers of texts you send will be added to this price! It is still cheap when compared to Belgium as long as you do as much as possible over mobile data which is currently possible with VOIP (Voice Over IP) and Messaging Services of Social Media.</p>
</div>
<div id="img-bic" class="imageblock">
<div class="content">
<img src="http://youri.discovers.asia/images/settling/bic.jpg" alt="bic.jpg">
</div>
<div class="title">Figure 8. Sašo showing which SIMs we considered to choose</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect2">
<h3 id="_commuter_pass">Commuter pass</h3>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>From September until December, I will travel 5 days a week to the Naganuma School to learn Japanese. In order to ease my commuting with public transport, I bought a PASMO card. It&#8217;s an IC card that allows you to charge money on it which you can use to travel around using public transport including trains, metro and buses. It is a must-have if you want to travel using public transport in a comfortable way. Otherwise, you&#8217;ll have to buy tickets at a counter everytime and this can become complicated if you need to transfer onto lines that are from another company. IC cards work on all the lines. There exist several types of cards and normally it doesn&#8217;t really matter which one you buy, <strong>UNLESS</strong> you want to charge a commuter pass on it. A commuter pass is a fee you pay to travel between 2 stations on a more regular basis. Therefore, it does matter which IC card you buy, because you are obliged to travel through at least one station of the company from which you bought the IC card. Therefore I had to get a PASMO card specifically, because I can travel to the school using the Tokyu Toyoko Line, which is owned by the Tokyu Coorporation. However, in the airport I bought another IC card, Suica. This card is offered by JR, a train company. Since I do not need to travel using a JR line, I was obliged to get the other IC card. Luckily, I can get a refund on my Suica if I return it to one of the JR stations, but for now I decided to keep it since it is a pretty card with a cute penguin on it. The commuter pass is valid for a month or 3 months. For my own safety I bought a 1-month commuter passes in case I might lose my PASMO card.</p>
</div>
<div id="img-pasmo" class="imageblock">
<div class="content">
<img src="http://youri.discovers.asia/images/settling/pasmo.jpg" alt="PASMO">
</div>
<div class="title">Figure 9. The very convenient PASMO card loaded with my commuter pass</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect2">
<h3 id="_get_internet_in_your_room_so_that_you_can_write_long_blog_posts">Get Internet in your room, so that you can write long blog posts</h3>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Leopalace21 provides its own Internet sevice to their appartments, which is called LEONET.
I simply had to make an account, pay for one month and all set and done: enjoy that unlimited downloading you&#8217;re used to! Only problem: the instructions were Japanese&#8230;&#8203;</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>After a couple of days trying to translate the instructions, the 3 Fujitsu guys figured out how to get stuff done and then we finally had Internet available in our appartments!
This was the final point on my bucket list to get done during the first weeks in Japan.
Now I can enjoy a comfortable life in my appartment with WiFi, travel easily to school or other destinations using public transport and get my scholarship to spend money!</p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>]]></description><link>http://youri.discovers.asia/2016/10/02/Settling-in-Japan.html</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://youri.discovers.asia/2016/10/02/Settling-in-Japan.html</guid><pubDate>Sun, 02 Oct 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Why I left]]></title><description><![CDATA[<div class="paragraph">
<p>After being already 10 days in Japan, I finally have found the opportunity to write my first post. We will start at the beginning, which is the reason why I left to Japan. Most of you know this already, but for the people that don&#8217;t, I&#8217;ll try to give a quick summary.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>During my first year of my Master&#8217;s program, I was already thinking about what I could do afterwards. Normally, one starts looking for a job or continues his/her studies with an additional Master&#8217;s program or PhD. I chose I could go for a PhD, since I would love to perform research in my further career and getting a PhD is in my opinion the right way to get into R&amp;D later on. However, having not that much practical experience in Computer Science, I wanted to gain some before starting a career.  That&#8217;s why I was planning to do an intern- or traineeship somewhere during summer.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>As most of you know, I am also a big fan of Japan. I love watching anime, but besides the wacko entertainment the Japanese provide, I also appreciate their ancient culture. I practice Jiu-Jitsu and I&#8217;d love to learn Kendo one day. I admire their spirit for perfectionism and their attitude to put collective harmony above personal benefit. Japan has been a source of inspiration since my childhood. That&#8217;s why I always was looking forward to visit the country one day.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Around November 2014, I received an e-mail from my faculty. It was forwarded publicity from our university&#8217;s International Relationships Office. I quickly skimmed the email and noticed it told about an international exchange program, Vulcanus, for scientists and engineers. You would get the opportunity to work in the research department of a multinational. This sounded very interesting, since I wanted to do an internship and on top of that, it concerned research. However, the fact that the internship would be international scared me a bit. Nevertheless, I read the email a second time, a bit more thoroughly and that&#8217;s when it happened. I discovered you would get a 4-month language course and afterwards start your 8-month traineeship in&#8230;&#8203; Japan.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>A whole year in the land of my dreams, gaining some practical experience in a research department and learn Japanese as a surplus. This email came like some revelation at that moment.  It combined all the topics that I was wondering about around that period. I decided to apply for this exchange program in my graduation year. This program lasts a whole year, which is why I wanted to finish my studies first. After filling in some forms, writing a CV and motivation letter, gathering documents from my university and an acknowledgement from my doctor that I&#8217;m in a proper condition to travel abroad, I had put everything together to apply for the <a href="http://www.eu-japan.eu/events/vulcanus-japan">Vulcanus in Japan</a> program, although without that much hope to succeed. It is an exchange program on European level, so I was convinced I wouldn&#8217;t be able to compete with the other applicants during the selection procedures. However, in February 2016 I got the verdict: I was selected to go to Japan. The committee that had selected me, recommended a particular traineeship at <a href="http://www.fujitsu.com/jp/group/labs/en/">Fujitsu Laboratories</a>. I had to write a motivation letter to the company and if I happened to be chosen by the company, I was ready to go.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>As you all know by now, Fujitsu Laboratories selected me for one of their internships and I am currently residing in Nakahara, Kawasaki City, in the Kanagawa prefecture, just outside of Tokyo. From September to December, I will daily commute to Shibuya, Tokyo to study Japanese at <a href="http://www.naganuma-school.ac.jp/">The Naganuma School, Tokyo School of Japanese Language</a>, together with the other 33 Vulcanus trainees. In my next post, I will talk more in detail about my flight and my first days in Japan.</p>
</div>]]></description><link>http://youri.discovers.asia/2016/09/12/Why-I-left.html</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://youri.discovers.asia/2016/09/12/Why-I-left.html</guid><pubDate>Mon, 12 Sep 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>