<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[Youri in Japan]]></title><description><![CDATA[My experiences in Japan during the Vulcanus in Japan 2016-2017 exchange program]]></description><link>https://endymion64.github.io</link><image><url>images/landscape_japan.svg</url><title>Youri in Japan</title><link>https://endymion64.github.io</link></image><generator>RSS for Node</generator><lastBuildDate>Mon, 23 Oct 2017 21:31:32 GMT</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://endymion64.github.io/rss/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><ttl>60</ttl><item><title><![CDATA[Winter Vacation, Part 1: 北海道]]></title><description><![CDATA[<div id="preamble">
<div class="sectionbody">
<div class="paragraph">
<p>I know, I know&#8230;&#8203; It&#8217;s been a while. 😅 My sincere apologies for being silent such a long time. As a matter of fact, I had lost my motivation to keep this blog alive, but my time in Japan is almost over, so let&#8217;s end it in beauty! There is still so much I could tell you all, so let&#8217;s try to get started again!</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>It&#8217;s my first blog post from 2017, so that means I still owe you all a Happy New Year, so&#8230;&#8203; Happy New Year everyone! <strong><em>&lt;insert party horn sound&gt;</em></strong> Now that the formalities are over, let&#8217;s get back to business and pick up where we ended: December 2016. It was, as usual, quite a busy month. The language course at the Naganuma School was about to end. As part of finalizing the course, we had to give a small presentation, in Japanese of course, about our studies and the coming internship. The school activities ended with a tears shedding graduation ceremony, followed by an even more emotional reception. The Vulcanus students spread their wings and settled across Japan to work in the research departments of famous Japanese multinationals.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>But before we jumped into work, it was time to enjoy a 3-week break. As to say, it was the longest break I will have had in Japan. Three whole weeks of pure freedom, so what did I do during that time? As you all might have thought, I enjoyed it by watching anime, reading manga, staying inside, playing videgames and avoiding sunlight as much as possible&#8230;&#8203; But since I&#8217;m used to do that in Belgium, I thought there could be some change for once. What I did instead was traveling to the most northern and southern part of Japan: Hokkaidou (北海道) and Okinawa (沖縄)!</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Since it&#8217;s been so long after the events, I forgot a lot of the details, but I&#8217;ll try somehow to make it an interesting story. This post will be about my time in Hokkaidou with Sašo and Ole. The pictures I took during this trip can be retrieved in the following <a href="https://goo.gl/photos/oQP3i9gk4wTV9jop6"><strong>album</strong></a>.</p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_day_1_sapporo">Day 1: Sapporo</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<div class="paragraph">
<p>In short, the first impression I had when arriving in New Chitose airport could be transcribed as follows: <em>"Oh look, there&#8217;s some snow. That&#8217;s cool&#8230;&#8203; And look over there, there&#8217;s more snow&#8230;&#8203; &lt;dramatic pause&gt;&#8230;&#8203; HOLY SHIIIT, THERE&#8217;S A FUCKTON OF SNOW EVERYWHERE!!!"</em>.
It must have been since my ski trip to Austria back in elementary school that I had seen that much snow at once. Everything was white: rooftops, nature, sidewalks, roads&#8230;&#8203; Everything, everywhere was covered by a white blanket.
We took the train to Sapporo and stayed in an AirBNB near Hokkaidou University for 4 days. The first day, we visited Sapporo itself.
The roads in Sapporo were covered in ice, yet traffic seemed not to obstructed. What I did remark was that the roads in Sapporo were much wider than the roads I was used to in Tokyo and Kawasaki.
The city itself sure shows a lot of American influences! Logical though, since Sapporo was built with the help of the American government back in the 19th century! Some historical sites really have that "Wild West" atmosphere, such as the Sapporo Clocktower and the Red Government Building.
Besides the historical sites, we also visited the Sapporo TV Tower (imagine the little brother of Tokyo Tower) and drank some Glühwhein at the German Christmas market over there. ('t was the season to be jolly after all&#8230;&#8203;)
After going for one of Hokkaidou&#8217;s famous dishes (soup curry, スープカレー) in a place called <a href="https://www.tripadvisor.com/Restaurant_Review-g298560-d3808559-Reviews-Soup_Curry_Samurai_Sakura-Sapporo_Hokkaido.html"><strong>Samurai Sakura</strong></a> (I highly recommend it!), we went out of the city and climbed up Mount Moiwa (藻岩山) by cable lift and stayed there for sunset in order to see Sapporo lighting up.
To end the day, we went back to Odori Park, in front of the Sapporo TV Tower, and enjoyed the illuminations over there. For me it was a first time visiting illuminations in Japan and I must say I was impressed. Winter Wonderland with thousands of lights in several colors reflecting against the snowy background really gives a soothing feeling.</p>
</div>
<div class="imageblock">
<div class="content">
<img src="https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/pQgBem_oRL6YjRIijB4uCsB8vlpMd3lBKrDEZhO2-NXBh-MsDkbZtYzJQc7QDidwnCqKNNCzoMbRpckXAir1oBuSoDJ64TCU219QNVA8UpFnk3356A3GF6gkZdB2fDxFfWTEGvswAsGPJG1JPUeu8YyGTzK1tVTtstKTSIPIRpWnmsSFuTukoGDurVESvLiVBcI8UAnZJWdh3qJBXiQXzuVHogFzm7XG9Pgq2YMujElBMXDhF1mCH3cVRDShbXkLtwqKAvQ6oYfaf9dx2ewLCeI3yTVAaHHz7jujMNWihtsWw4ptlyH5jN2zPDb33Sk5-qkDh8wJocppQ93fRWez9n6pC5yoonnXQup-ij_wFGK0x3a37BQenSEZ3rBj4TAkIny42cviL0SmbBAIRNFdq_wTd9oyvxTEwerWu5O41Y0VTxTfuZVUNWO-idFSZC0Q-rONiNu949zbyPQtNzjkqgedyU4DDW7q3zdS-fSSDTZrHrF9IwX1rjUV_QiqW-Z0luRwoeu0R6huKTRGZxACuvbTwf_pg4oS5_AwYCm8FFcL4E3CTJpLXS4K9NCOqE7rHR46IR790uqq3zT6HsHUdxs2_algeSF45-PMNpHuP9xxbZMfZbuy5GRt0k7OZs_31xeCBD5w-gLQ9y5NAgHQD-G7wNvuLjblERbZLXGegA=w1267-h950-no" alt="pQgBem oRL6YjRIijB4uCsB8vlpMd3lBKrDEZhO2 NXBh MsDkbZtYzJQc7QDidwnCqKNNCzoMbRpckXAir1oBuSoDJ64TCU219QNVA8UpFnk3356A3GF6gkZdB2fDxFfWTEGvswAsGPJG1JPUeu8YyGTzK1tVTtstKTSIPIRpWnmsSFuTukoGDurVESvLiVBcI8UAnZJWdh3qJBXiQXzuVHogFzm7XG9Pgq2YMujElBMXDhF1mCH3cVRDShbXkLtwqKAvQ6oYfaf9dx2ewLCeI3yTVAaHHz7jujMNWihtsWw4ptlyH5jN2zPDb33Sk5 qkDh8wJocppQ93fRWez9n6pC5yoonnXQup ij wFGK0x3a37BQenSEZ3rBj4TAkIny42cviL0SmbBAIRNFdq wTd9oyvxTEwerWu5O41Y0VTxTfuZVUNWO idFSZC0Q rONiNu949zbyPQtNzjkqgedyU4DDW7q3zdS fSSDTZrHrF9IwX1rjUV QiqW Z0luRwoeu0R6huKTRGZxACuvbTwf pg4oS5 AwYCm8FFcL4E3CTJpLXS4K9NCOqE7rHR46IR790uqq3zT6HsHUdxs2 algeSF45 PMNpHuP9xxbZMfZbuy5GRt0k7OZs 31xeCBD5w gLQ9y5NAgHQD G7wNvuLjblERbZLXGegA=w1267 h950 no">
</div>
<div class="title">Figure 1. The Red Government Building</div>
</div>
<div class="imageblock">
<div class="content">
<img src="https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/2PP5bedaJJn09dsGZifjEtu7_z-PnFyN-9Y6DL3sN4J7UPPzRWE-Sw2lUs6GFOBh5z9HLS-KURpVOU1_OWnwvzUPaokM9m4LE62jt3MtViJqMsvjrsJyEQuWdhrjp5QSNyl6G0EhwLku1vPRNpYE3JFbtKgMSIbXk6R7fi0oiPBsPhWrGZOgfBfj6RluqpQU-Jx9_6NWDq7I_AIEg_zvDuLcW8i1_AfzxG5K-97esSK-4dYO-h1Vi7Wru3-Ff4AJwkd9bc9jAPmEly3jU4b81JhTdL3MhIUL3ynqL_ElT7SIMq0TLJrWXFFn3s1jhXX3E2r2FH3smLl5-PD2wfLoMRxS0KZ-Ae-_QuxLJgTWGMOU9NdUBUykcjBXQnI4lFHaExE_AbU7T8osF4gESxUZgmttpJBEU89uMJunSKFWKfNNAHaAxS66vV4Ys4qv7zjpSILFLk9CoT7sRI7B4rWMqguWRAT5HKIYCe7dVcFdChhgylWA5UYK4ZktnR2TtopCqBtyziOmSxMYPZRX1N-lwoIa-he-EIOd2uE4y7MBTnDQpeGY98AQeih8LEnoVzc6TuetYuA5LxRhBV6Qjw5SBJ2TxAUCXoz0K18gWb90fOII0XUVwAdWcdSh2lTeOQg6NI2Vb19Nod8xmnBXtXKhh9bDAi3OKbjvons3JXI45Q=w1267-h950-no" alt="2PP5bedaJJn09dsGZifjEtu7 z PnFyN 9Y6DL3sN4J7UPPzRWE Sw2lUs6GFOBh5z9HLS KURpVOU1 OWnwvzUPaokM9m4LE62jt3MtViJqMsvjrsJyEQuWdhrjp5QSNyl6G0EhwLku1vPRNpYE3JFbtKgMSIbXk6R7fi0oiPBsPhWrGZOgfBfj6RluqpQU Jx9 6NWDq7I AIEg zvDuLcW8i1 AfzxG5K 97esSK 4dYO h1Vi7Wru3 Ff4AJwkd9bc9jAPmEly3jU4b81JhTdL3MhIUL3ynqL ElT7SIMq0TLJrWXFFn3s1jhXX3E2r2FH3smLl5 PD2wfLoMRxS0KZ Ae  QuxLJgTWGMOU9NdUBUykcjBXQnI4lFHaExE AbU7T8osF4gESxUZgmttpJBEU89uMJunSKFWKfNNAHaAxS66vV4Ys4qv7zjpSILFLk9CoT7sRI7B4rWMqguWRAT5HKIYCe7dVcFdChhgylWA5UYK4ZktnR2TtopCqBtyziOmSxMYPZRX1N lwoIa he EIOd2uE4y7MBTnDQpeGY98AQeih8LEnoVzc6TuetYuA5LxRhBV6Qjw5SBJ2TxAUCXoz0K18gWb90fOII0XUVwAdWcdSh2lTeOQg6NI2Vb19Nod8xmnBXtXKhh9bDAi3OKbjvons3JXI45Q=w1267 h950 no">
</div>
<div class="title">Figure 2. For whom the bell tolls? Sapporo of course!</div>
</div>
<div class="imageblock">
<div class="content">
<img src="https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/GZe0Rff_WcImbU8du0i82IvEnlEWR-oD8aBlDUuvmbIuix08bLNPJMY71gbtJYNf4MP3_lbyu5XUn_3pHCxkeo54U2hoG7-vfn6jUMxXCmfsxZA61-9-oYQ18r2O_qBygEgQh9ZG-ECT0emErTg5DF-YeVHEn4PWhCNY56QdcUnaqZku8FQPd9_R24KqJZf5TUeogqql7ojspj6_LoYox0OsflQIwjKy1J29Kdpt8fNMZfKhfuHg-XvWfYIwv_B5IOObPLcvCpd8oorglGN22cQyA2UNuFHwO3QDhaY-k0BCLbfoY6ulkTcJ3WMzYq2JOJIIjk5VQq7HkSOwVGXon_s3fEb5kat0l-mVPcGD9mMuTBUIsN1eybSTe0Wr6pz1bCN_io-u4EAV6hbwPurbUhHrZvqRjnl-SaDONPXDmzg_OMpXE5Rd48magU02lAcu1TsyLd15-3gsSkG-bl7dnRIbZEMG8dpV-UE4YVg9Jg3rO3XbHisMpR4BQLujyttmDbjP_jeb7KJbqcVBoHL5mOWV2nwknaTUCVcd1YaZ_hKLnJuNUGY0LTANj0GJLawcDT4Vc5gelr8t3kpCvxfVEsTgiv6bxg_P4tpsDIp7KYwPKUG3D1_0yu8yDOtbbmZ9AHNZhk6JzJfY54EQl4RdU76mS9HJGMBAHlzLWMfAZA=w713-h950-no" alt="GZe0Rff WcImbU8du0i82IvEnlEWR oD8aBlDUuvmbIuix08bLNPJMY71gbtJYNf4MP3 lbyu5XUn 3pHCxkeo54U2hoG7 vfn6jUMxXCmfsxZA61 9 oYQ18r2O qBygEgQh9ZG ECT0emErTg5DF YeVHEn4PWhCNY56QdcUnaqZku8FQPd9 R24KqJZf5TUeogqql7ojspj6 LoYox0OsflQIwjKy1J29Kdpt8fNMZfKhfuHg XvWfYIwv B5IOObPLcvCpd8oorglGN22cQyA2UNuFHwO3QDhaY k0BCLbfoY6ulkTcJ3WMzYq2JOJIIjk5VQq7HkSOwVGXon s3fEb5kat0l mVPcGD9mMuTBUIsN1eybSTe0Wr6pz1bCN io u4EAV6hbwPurbUhHrZvqRjnl SaDONPXDmzg OMpXE5Rd48magU02lAcu1TsyLd15 3gsSkG bl7dnRIbZEMG8dpV UE4YVg9Jg3rO3XbHisMpR4BQLujyttmDbjP jeb7KJbqcVBoHL5mOWV2nwknaTUCVcd1YaZ hKLnJuNUGY0LTANj0GJLawcDT4Vc5gelr8t3kpCvxfVEsTgiv6bxg P4tpsDIp7KYwPKUG3D1 0yu8yDOtbbmZ9AHNZhk6JzJfY54EQl4RdU76mS9HJGMBAHlzLWMfAZA=w713 h950 no">
</div>
<div class="title">Figure 3. Sapporo&#8217;s own Tokyo Tower</div>
</div>
<div class="imageblock">
<div class="content">
<img src="https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/4Paqa4OPwIxu0-Iv6ftEd0fR0LIScN4vfG-z66FV_sQXDvHy2e4yPikI5DnZiR0tQogr2w_7bkQi-rRjm6jf6VVS10iGWHCl9M4Gw9e3bJWVr0B9jiALWLdV-eb2VeIWHf14MyykTjTWQ4ksTJGG0bq0PkgdsONya1qxscDqIHBEJ_3y1eEnqTvOsv_KeeCGeRmwzVd6l1ygxOdv7NXnh7jMKz7XfMyzKyoa4jwhXz-bXSQwPUOMewdLRuMArjlF7tZAP1DYfh6qZpv3npyCFKb7HP_PrAwgkeHepw-g2tSF4GaPYs0tUJEGwkzmY3BirQRvAfTqXtI5EPPI-7uvnMlxpeplLpVVm_v-aOFJZ1S1KX3KC0tI_il9rrcPjqaaD99zqgmRjkfPKmtqcmckRxqJ-2grBA7PQSx-XPqYsuUorma9YDI7oAxQs7IfAzd-dWXsMxZpjfeSTG2OEmHURXZ1H0aKe9lzqTd-8Yechig__oyMaA5ZPSzYqG-8HUZqom6XB9P4lQNV2s5mfok9LVREYq0JidMO2H_gKRzxfL_u2zI_KmTTcX30WCnZos17WnU4sDwfd0R7a9fu_vWmVRcWhirUWa3FCa9ldINec26ZCBuxvmCCZXP06PeXPUUM_QE15fNFsb6ufy4XgNTe0xJrLhrzMqo8wDa8x44BSA=w1267-h950-no" alt="4Paqa4OPwIxu0 Iv6ftEd0fR0LIScN4vfG z66FV sQXDvHy2e4yPikI5DnZiR0tQogr2w 7bkQi rRjm6jf6VVS10iGWHCl9M4Gw9e3bJWVr0B9jiALWLdV eb2VeIWHf14MyykTjTWQ4ksTJGG0bq0PkgdsONya1qxscDqIHBEJ 3y1eEnqTvOsv KeeCGeRmwzVd6l1ygxOdv7NXnh7jMKz7XfMyzKyoa4jwhXz bXSQwPUOMewdLRuMArjlF7tZAP1DYfh6qZpv3npyCFKb7HP PrAwgkeHepw g2tSF4GaPYs0tUJEGwkzmY3BirQRvAfTqXtI5EPPI 7uvnMlxpeplLpVVm v aOFJZ1S1KX3KC0tI il9rrcPjqaaD99zqgmRjkfPKmtqcmckRxqJ 2grBA7PQSx XPqYsuUorma9YDI7oAxQs7IfAzd dWXsMxZpjfeSTG2OEmHURXZ1H0aKe9lzqTd 8Yechig  oyMaA5ZPSzYqG 8HUZqom6XB9P4lQNV2s5mfok9LVREYq0JidMO2H gKRzxfL u2zI KmTTcX30WCnZos17WnU4sDwfd0R7a9fu vWmVRcWhirUWa3FCa9ldINec26ZCBuxvmCCZXP06PeXPUUM QE15fNFsb6ufy4XgNTe0xJrLhrzMqo8wDa8x44BSA=w1267 h950 no">
</div>
<div class="title">Figure 4. OOOOOOH! Shiiiiinyyyyyy 😍</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_day_2_teine_ski_resort">Day 2: Teine ski resort</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<div class="paragraph">
<p>The second day, we went skiing on Mount Teine, just outside of Sapporo. We had a bright sky that day. On the mountain, we had a great overview of Sapporo, and could even see the Japanese Sea (Ishikari Bay to be more precise).
The ski slopes were very nice! We mostly took the long track which was about 4 kilometers long. Of course, being as excited as I was, I was being a speed-devil from time to time, with the result I made some gracious face plants. Luckily I didn&#8217;t get any injuries or fractures!</p>
</div>
<div class="imageblock">
<div class="content">
<img src="https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/o5G0gnrpndMy971dLIlHKgO5pfqPIo0VfE9i7m4AlLMhpg4FRMuO0UVISrIwZS7gwj_maNjoDzyXrvsV7TANZOmgf2VD_MEkWmWdxkGGLZrYju6Za7BCUGdZK3gdJna8r3KM5KErCVfDFChRjJvYkmHqFvbFlZFJZ_udH6OKhTGlFep6njpZigvM5EuiW5SEyV6oLXb2WXHH3sDVo2j4WcAXqE4T9fom6rRTScZDB9JwskNvOLZ0jwZDcb_ub3Z-gmpwH5vcG9ltaRcZ5cAMn4rbD-xvZOBwKp90i2m40TXuI-S-mVopJhME9Ao7sb2mSfao7qKJUmxh_JCu_lEp_RLyH62KqJbn0X1qYRp9Wya5K_s4uTUBXZU13uhzBeq8644084MyktyC6AJxMIh5ywU-FEwFzlV2kJF8-j3WWaZqch3b36OQnwFH9r55ZTx2ZhperYE5dNZZjAN61xyD2jxf8puE4Cu68OpZ2poUWjRlk1MES6Fh68hnONGGBkvBwP5FQ5Q0vOEexnA9KwOA9WjJzkSSoZV4l2F5K1ONjFGpE2z4BQT-SL-DiFvIZkpLTwrh6yqkzFWX8PmngqJ1Oswx2q26--Ts0WVE7HesWrQ1941W4TKMRLTOEeuE8wa6O3XC7TZKtgpf7S5mLGq1WgNL1nocWUxuwKoF9bsSUw=w1267-h950-no" alt="o5G0gnrpndMy971dLIlHKgO5pfqPIo0VfE9i7m4AlLMhpg4FRMuO0UVISrIwZS7gwj maNjoDzyXrvsV7TANZOmgf2VD MEkWmWdxkGGLZrYju6Za7BCUGdZK3gdJna8r3KM5KErCVfDFChRjJvYkmHqFvbFlZFJZ udH6OKhTGlFep6njpZigvM5EuiW5SEyV6oLXb2WXHH3sDVo2j4WcAXqE4T9fom6rRTScZDB9JwskNvOLZ0jwZDcb ub3Z gmpwH5vcG9ltaRcZ5cAMn4rbD xvZOBwKp90i2m40TXuI S mVopJhME9Ao7sb2mSfao7qKJUmxh JCu lEp RLyH62KqJbn0X1qYRp9Wya5K s4uTUBXZU13uhzBeq8644084MyktyC6AJxMIh5ywU FEwFzlV2kJF8 j3WWaZqch3b36OQnwFH9r55ZTx2ZhperYE5dNZZjAN61xyD2jxf8puE4Cu68OpZ2poUWjRlk1MES6Fh68hnONGGBkvBwP5FQ5Q0vOEexnA9KwOA9WjJzkSSoZV4l2F5K1ONjFGpE2z4BQT SL DiFvIZkpLTwrh6yqkzFWX8PmngqJ1Oswx2q26  Ts0WVE7HesWrQ1941W4TKMRLTOEeuE8wa6O3XC7TZKtgpf7S5mLGq1WgNL1nocWUxuwKoF9bsSUw=w1267 h950 no">
</div>
<div class="title">Figure 5. Skiing with an ocean view</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_day_3_otaru">Day 3: Otaru</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<div class="paragraph">
<p>On the third day of <strike>Christmas</strike> the Hokkaidou trip, we visited the old harbor town, Otaru, which had a rather worn out impression to be honest. The architecture over there again showed a lot of Western influences.
The village itself was not as amusing as expected, it was rather focused on souvenirs. Most of the shops also sold the same type of articles: glass work, liquor, chocolates etc.
For lunch, we ate Genghis Khan (ジンギスカン). Yup that&#8217;s right: we ate the Mongolian conqueror from the 12th and 13th century! He tasted like grilled mutton meat.
The most attracting site in Otaru is the canal and the lantern path over there, but we didn&#8217;t stay for the nightfall to see the lanterns lighting up.</p>
</div>
<div class="imageblock">
<div class="content">
<img src="https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/6aKNx_O_X8TOshxzqTxEMQ6-gBitgpFv4FN8rCSYGgd1NG9B7YmrMO7jED-2fAXbD-SSC_Re2DnZR4qfaWejW2y8si1fSgRWSeP9RBKQdQEkEOB6ESdI0P4O_6jxHq1AUq5SqSWIFiOw0l4LBbvYORfspzp-5j_OpCiuv_Elpw-owWdrCCYbiUu9OuDDdloPI9yEZ4O3KEK3D2RosORB60UMKAGgn-zV8Meicw_IeMpzdrtlljoOTT_1eezuNatWm8bUThP2_nvp1vDzAMaK2Hf4ixL6GGCNpK__pi0DkrZ89xe-t0hGYbnwqpBbhBZGCBDnz9fp0YsdJdTz3rhrJksgee_PJVtiGuV-05_7OrYE-LvVtekClVSR_qZMY83bT-IlQErA3Oyx-J0A0NrSFRLPrR2t4KkYd9yIWZncnRPl1s9b1sAnvY_CiWyX3WOPQxd2ltEUYwvbZSsnN51EGLt92x2Fn3ipnt--f8qRYbLPCYW0SYy8mwn7Cd0KqJLpFR4V0sb2hyEPo6wfeRfSpYt1acCKm67K5mI5SA6n39nC1DQC5K7fz2-zU1VlqqX9X_kS4ETviEseq4mRoyJGqnQJ3wiz1EzGcV-Cb8Yv02dT5JfSkBruOlHN427I2FFj-X2Ur0uc_Xl7AcR-zRzOOj_bjMSDkHwR2HaQLXL3iQ=w1267-h950-no" alt="6aKNx O X8TOshxzqTxEMQ6 gBitgpFv4FN8rCSYGgd1NG9B7YmrMO7jED 2fAXbD SSC Re2DnZR4qfaWejW2y8si1fSgRWSeP9RBKQdQEkEOB6ESdI0P4O 6jxHq1AUq5SqSWIFiOw0l4LBbvYORfspzp 5j OpCiuv Elpw owWdrCCYbiUu9OuDDdloPI9yEZ4O3KEK3D2RosORB60UMKAGgn zV8Meicw IeMpzdrtlljoOTT 1eezuNatWm8bUThP2 nvp1vDzAMaK2Hf4ixL6GGCNpK  pi0DkrZ89xe t0hGYbnwqpBbhBZGCBDnz9fp0YsdJdTz3rhrJksgee PJVtiGuV 05 7OrYE LvVtekClVSR qZMY83bT IlQErA3Oyx J0A0NrSFRLPrR2t4KkYd9yIWZncnRPl1s9b1sAnvY CiWyX3WOPQxd2ltEUYwvbZSsnN51EGLt92x2Fn3ipnt  f8qRYbLPCYW0SYy8mwn7Cd0KqJLpFR4V0sb2hyEPo6wfeRfSpYt1acCKm67K5mI5SA6n39nC1DQC5K7fz2 zU1VlqqX9X kS4ETviEseq4mRoyJGqnQJ3wiz1EzGcV Cb8Yv02dT5JfSkBruOlHN427I2FFj X2Ur0uc Xl7AcR zRzOOj bjMSDkHwR2HaQLXL3iQ=w1267 h950 no">
</div>
<div class="title">Figure 6. The canal in Otaru</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_day_4_noboribetsu_onsen">Day 4: Noboribetsu Onsen</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Our final day in Hokkaidou, we left the AirBNB and took the bus to one of the most famous areas on the island: Noboribetsu! After so many cold days, it was time to go warm up a bit in the natural hot springs over there. Entering the onsen village, you&#8217;ll be greeted by red and blue Oni (鬼,  a kind of youkai from Japanese folklore, variously translated as demons, devils, ogres, or trolls).</p>
</div>
<div class="imageblock">
<div class="content">
<img src="https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/1mJ7QIvv7NTnulwIG3QT6_2Z14j-FbrZjbIcV9AZ94h3_bEn5sIso2qe1xcvB1h8djmvwGkb2tan3Ywh9NBmioZquG7uAW0m6_JAby8fxjsC5_LVRU1beS9-DJbBEmwdCKa0p31_vcF225IIQMteB-y8wot91VbeKac94-se4HHbtdFhI1xQk9T-ilpv_8rKz5M_shsXYISAH_Ve6u3YDaThR-3ioFM5e0sxiZpd-A9maN_UHjuL0cl-jFu-RMvgMt0Fpg7RUvxHrDkMs_bTbfHje0a7oVzHsjjzwiKaJXJSM0Dcnp6-rQUq1knanpzIFwj9V_XBKEn5_GHgRlnwgD2cEpE1CcGc7KmXBgdafj5VfFCYBtX7GNzPxFewZZAVnoxCUt8yrbNJDQ7ekURRk-MIGfKj2t_uw3dqD_wCVkeUBSm6OYgkCV244CtF_VOhZaQxzyIOwXKpgEgBDj4KO3b-5jXvY8Kl1WVExfliC6XJ-UolhVHHxTFRIcMiaoeBIndt0n7Sz8gb4wO4KomPcBAtezMgOLIRq7ecDKt-C--UuH7juwnb1pZ-TH3A9HFkkioIE6SGwhiITGVlFN5GC3gANqQbVZB2ql29bjfelUQnM-H5nky8SBekqB-RoGYTg37pvdkJASkNQBbdqRuoWOPMJI6G4KJrgxwqJ1WIBg=w713-h950-no" alt="1mJ7QIvv7NTnulwIG3QT6 2Z14j FbrZjbIcV9AZ94h3 bEn5sIso2qe1xcvB1h8djmvwGkb2tan3Ywh9NBmioZquG7uAW0m6 JAby8fxjsC5 LVRU1beS9 DJbBEmwdCKa0p31 vcF225IIQMteB y8wot91VbeKac94 se4HHbtdFhI1xQk9T ilpv 8rKz5M shsXYISAH Ve6u3YDaThR 3ioFM5e0sxiZpd A9maN UHjuL0cl jFu RMvgMt0Fpg7RUvxHrDkMs bTbfHje0a7oVzHsjjzwiKaJXJSM0Dcnp6 rQUq1knanpzIFwj9V XBKEn5 GHgRlnwgD2cEpE1CcGc7KmXBgdafj5VfFCYBtX7GNzPxFewZZAVnoxCUt8yrbNJDQ7ekURRk MIGfKj2t uw3dqD wCVkeUBSm6OYgkCV244CtF VOhZaQxzyIOwXKpgEgBDj4KO3b 5jXvY8Kl1WVExfliC6XJ UolhVHHxTFRIcMiaoeBIndt0n7Sz8gb4wO4KomPcBAtezMgOLIRq7ecDKt C  UuH7juwnb1pZ TH3A9HFkkioIE6SGwhiITGVlFN5GC3gANqQbVZB2ql29bjfelUQnM H5nky8SBekqB RoGYTg37pvdkJASkNQBbdqRuoWOPMJI6G4KJrgxwqJ1WIBg=w713 h950 no">
</div>
<div class="title">Figure 7. Cute little beasty, isn&#8217;t it?</div>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Before checking-in at our hotel, we walked around a bit around the village. To our surprises, there is a bear park, but we didn&#8217;t enter it, since we weren&#8217;t that interested.
We walked by the village&#8217;s Geyser, which is sited underneath a traffic road, met The King of Hell in his temple: <a href="https://www.tripadvisor.com/Attraction_Review-g325583-d6839624-Reviews-Enmado-Noboribetsu_Hokkaido.html"><strong>Enma-dou</strong></a>(閻魔堂), and walked to the Hell Valley (地獄谷, jigokudani): the sulfurous, volcanic main source of Noboribetsu&#8217;s hot spring waters. The smell of sulfur hangs everywhere, but the view is majestic.</p>
</div>
<div class="imageblock">
<div class="content">
<img src="https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/SERv674Eqpbz4z6M6-UXdJ5GB9VPoz0j5bDaUwXG4ld8hB2G0E3UdXzEwvqtjzJ6Xca0bJZQwPEieW7lRY8oA5TSG-2mBQRgliv7-FJGAeLlnTjBNb3SzpNpUBIn_7EbWEGFMTPN39eCOy8STCjS2icUYXOL-MlGEKi1CzZGBcOdNx8gkbz_PTgguQynexDVCsAvZSTFyONoZ8jvrMKW2G1hl-0uTwhfi8LaLbgfRg6g7HzVirJD5Fp-zX3RHxosih6bJj0JAYfe8MpVTy4gbA0hXmIB5ejsxvaNaXlaPncAkp-reby6wKEZ4fXx47_RRjAeVUX-UNkdRLit3j6Eccxk_zkUHvZpGQhpjqAmMj29YDuKWGM9HDhrGvn9aAWvjtYNmNdo2WGsWtDyEjBB6RiO77STsWIIdBHZbSwJw7PIQ22D6mKRfn-dLV7epcc7JfgjxRxS1qosunCLdqEHC2LCJdMUAFAGqRrTpSNgz6GFkPsCwURRRZ1DdW9czsKaPlbvjhxbwBvQnaYrmsojdVS2Cg_diHAGnDPJ8qPNNILQUD2rjMwzMF9z2nM1Mo3jtVldKwspC2YDDxcSdhVNANXlnyzDwRn-30JUsn_qiTgbi7nfbW3IQ572KYOszmC7YzMnhNoR1_JijnyGbGv-Yv-g02FiWNpIq-EZEzJDSw=w1267-h950-no" alt="SERv674Eqpbz4z6M6 UXdJ5GB9VPoz0j5bDaUwXG4ld8hB2G0E3UdXzEwvqtjzJ6Xca0bJZQwPEieW7lRY8oA5TSG 2mBQRgliv7 FJGAeLlnTjBNb3SzpNpUBIn 7EbWEGFMTPN39eCOy8STCjS2icUYXOL MlGEKi1CzZGBcOdNx8gkbz PTgguQynexDVCsAvZSTFyONoZ8jvrMKW2G1hl 0uTwhfi8LaLbgfRg6g7HzVirJD5Fp zX3RHxosih6bJj0JAYfe8MpVTy4gbA0hXmIB5ejsxvaNaXlaPncAkp reby6wKEZ4fXx47 RRjAeVUX UNkdRLit3j6Eccxk zkUHvZpGQhpjqAmMj29YDuKWGM9HDhrGvn9aAWvjtYNmNdo2WGsWtDyEjBB6RiO77STsWIIdBHZbSwJw7PIQ22D6mKRfn dLV7epcc7JfgjxRxS1qosunCLdqEHC2LCJdMUAFAGqRrTpSNgz6GFkPsCwURRRZ1DdW9czsKaPlbvjhxbwBvQnaYrmsojdVS2Cg diHAGnDPJ8qPNNILQUD2rjMwzMF9z2nM1Mo3jtVldKwspC2YDDxcSdhVNANXlnyzDwRn 30JUsn qiTgbi7nfbW3IQ572KYOszmC7YzMnhNoR1 JijnyGbGv Yv g02FiWNpIq EZEzJDSw=w1267 h950 no">
</div>
<div class="title">Figure 8. Entering Hell Valley</div>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>We stayed the night in a hotel with Japanese decorated rooms, which means we had to sleep in a futon on a tatami floor. We got a Yukata to walk around in the hotel and the onsen. It was very relaxing (apart from the majority of Chinese tourists during dinner who apparently don&#8217;t understand the purpose of queues at the buffet and are not ashamed of turning their tables into a dump&#8230;&#8203;).
After a good night&#8217;s rest and a final 6 A.M. morning dive in the onsen, we went back to New Chitose Airport and said goodbye to Japan&#8217;s Winter Wonderland of the North.</p>
</div>
</div>
</div>]]></description><link>https://endymion64.github.io/2017/07/01/Winter-Vacation-Part-1.html</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://endymion64.github.io/2017/07/01/Winter-Vacation-Part-1.html</guid><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jul 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[November Update]]></title><description><![CDATA[<div class="paragraph">
<p>It has been a whole month since I made my last post.
Time just keeps flying&#8230;&#8203;
The final weeks at Naganuma School have started.
All of a sudden, I start to realize that the end of a hard, tough, but yet oh so fulfilling period in my lifetime is nearing.
Next week, I will have my final presentation, my graduation ceremony from Naganuma School.
I&#8217;ll have to prove to the outside world what 3 months of cramming words, verbs and grammar into your head can result in.
But I don&#8217;t have to do it alone, the presentations are done in groups of 2 people.
I was coupled to my buddy, Shaikh, from the Netherlands.
We are currently finishing our script and I can say to feel satisfied about the result.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>What actually began as a blog post about an afternoon spent listening to two great bands, turned out into a compilation of what I have experienced through November since I haven&#8217;t written anything here for a while.
And since I had a rare free evening in the middle of a school week, I realised I could finally start to spit my gut properly.
So be prepared for a rather long story.
Grab you popcorn, fetch some coke, sit down and here we go!</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Let me start by saying this: school was rather tough for me in November.
I think I started to get tired of continuously stuffing my head with new content every night.
From the moment I wake up, until the last second I fall asleep, my mind is trying to process new, freshly learnt Japanese.
We have come to a point that the number of words and verbs we have encountered are that numereous, you cannot use them anymore on a regular basis.
Result: you start to forget, you start to forget a lot!
The only manner to regain forgotten knowledge: review it.
The thing is, I don&#8217;t find the motivation to do this properly, since I already cram those daily 30 new words in my head and these words are at that point in time more important to me than the previous 628 (to give it a random number).
But I have let the frustration behind me and took peace with the fact that my brain cannot simply remember words that I only have encountered once on a piece of paper and never properly used in my daily life ever since.
I am sure I will find some time and motivation in the future to properly review those once I have had my break during the Holidays.
To strengthen this statement: I bought a vocabulary book to study for my second JLPT attempt in July 2017.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Now that I have mentioned JLPT, allow me to explain shortly what it is. <a href="http://www.jlpt.jp/e/"><strong>JLPT</strong></a> is the abbreviation for Japanese Language Proficiency Test. It is an examination to, surprise surprise, measure your Japanese language proficiency and grants you a nice, official piece of paper stating your level when succeeded.
The examination is done twice per year and you can apply for one of the 5 available levels, starting on the bottom with N5 (the easiest) and ending with N1 (the toughest).
Last week, I took the N4 exam.
The content of my language course exceeds the border of the N5 level by dozens of miles, so I was ambitious to apply for the next level.
The only thing that is not really covered good by the course are Kanji, which were crucial for the vocabulary part of the exam.
For N4, you should know around 285 characters plus a ton of words you can spell with them.
Being to exhausted from daily school life, I only studied 120 Kanji (enough for N5).
Hence, the exam went as I had expected: I had enough knowledge for the grammar part, listening went rather easy, but I simply don&#8217;t know enough Kanjis for the vocabulary part.
Since that part went rather bad, I doubt I will pass the exam, but I will get my official result at the end of January.
I still have the examination moment in July, for which I will have more time to prepare properly, but being ambitious as always, I will try to achieve the N3 level!</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>If people start to think all of sudden I have had no life outside of my language studies, don&#8217;t worry!
On Friday nights I visited the local izakayas in my ward with Sašo, Ole and other friends I made during my volounteer classes at Musashi Kosugi station and got in touch with some local folks over there.
It&#8217;s a great way to practise some casualy spoken Japanese.
I also went to the <a href="http://fes16.moshimoshi-nippon.jp/en/"><strong>Moshi Moshi Nippon Festival 2016</strong></a>.
It&#8217;s a festival promoting Japan&#8217;s teen and pop culture.
A nice thing about the festival is that it was free for gaikokujin (外国人, foreigner), or for short gaijin, but you had to register to get inside the venue.
The festival was held in Tokyo Taiikakun, at the border of Shinjuku and Shibuya.
Outside the building, there was an free-entry zone with food stands and an outdoor stage.
Drinks were very cheap when compared to Belgian festivals.
Inside, you had various booths and 2 stages with various performances.
Despite having great names in the line up, the number of people attending the event was rather small.
The event site itself was also smaller than I had expected and the booths were mostly focused on the female products like make-up and girl-magazines.
There was a Resident Evil booth though where you could play a demo of the soon releasing new game with Playstation VR, but I couldn&#8217;t fetch a ticket unfortunately.
I wouldn&#8217;t spend my whole weekend there, but I certainly had a lot of fun for one full afternoon.
I expected an overcrowded site, but this wasn&#8217;t absolutely the case.</p>
</div>
<div id="img-moshimoshi" class="imageblock">
<div class="content">
<img src="https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/-4gZmY9mmG21S_JMwruci-TW-Ifgy66br-TFIv637xn9A_l3KzFFb62uYsUy1BKcVSH5YURaCJ29u7sp7K0nPws8AE-Q4Q-dJ4CtEHCX2Q-o1JFKGEfpCLYdrTLMP5tnFUipo5m08H6oiA4XRd3r_LvBitFRw60c06NZJPeB-VXYCpCLISvqNwL_W0FhkfFtQUsC3006CdWULgmt3-ZcOq4S2BsTR2QU0JraCQdr-w9hiEXMB3tFSkZP4WWJayxL2g-Kb_pOYRmKwi-iIEAlvKJAJk9E7opHELYCFS0f9wfP5GOF2qoPWytRkQkTzprIDnW8SNLRyDqHnUJRMJztcW6w0hN0SXjLLjep12bqSttalFfSi-0F2vtuj7GF_wWaxOrIWQD7l-7Hs0tiutIHANoGWT0f1QNn9vfxjsw0pAwoKqYtNlPUtJdOqOD_qq3w876Wd3AmFgw3h_HT-tiPoIUnNNU_NAdKZRdWNdyrbGDlTjV7-2qSGTj1dVaev5-2q4_3nwAg2M_6xEFm6T5eE1aRqPIM95n15pChpZl3UBDvGRGQfrJzhWEu3VJ5kI2ePC71o34X0TiBRPylR1yBFoo10U_Bj1p0A1NoJ-yiQgeQyWnFSBGSJfK91pOMFfaMRyusg1bDXqZU10P2I2UVqAN6i1US5ij57FULd2KO-g=w950-h713-no" alt=" 4gZmY9mmG21S JMwruci TW Ifgy66br TFIv637xn9A l3KzFFb62uYsUy1BKcVSH5YURaCJ29u7sp7K0nPws8AE Q4Q dJ4CtEHCX2Q o1JFKGEfpCLYdrTLMP5tnFUipo5m08H6oiA4XRd3r LvBitFRw60c06NZJPeB VXYCpCLISvqNwL W0FhkfFtQUsC3006CdWULgmt3 ZcOq4S2BsTR2QU0JraCQdr w9hiEXMB3tFSkZP4WWJayxL2g Kb pOYRmKwi iIEAlvKJAJk9E7opHELYCFS0f9wfP5GOF2qoPWytRkQkTzprIDnW8SNLRyDqHnUJRMJztcW6w0hN0SXjLLjep12bqSttalFfSi 0F2vtuj7GF wWaxOrIWQD7l 7Hs0tiutIHANoGWT0f1QNn9vfxjsw0pAwoKqYtNlPUtJdOqOD qq3w876Wd3AmFgw3h HT tiPoIUnNNU NAdKZRdWNdyrbGDlTjV7 2qSGTj1dVaev5 2q4 3nwAg2M 6xEFm6T5eE1aRqPIM95n15pChpZl3UBDvGRGQfrJzhWEu3VJ5kI2ePC71o34X0TiBRPylR1yBFoo10U Bj1p0A1NoJ yiQgeQyWnFSBGSJfK91pOMFfaMRyusg1bDXqZU10P2I2UVqAN6i1US5ij57FULd2KO g=w950 h713 no">
</div>
<div class="title">Figure 1. Overview of Moshi Moshi Nippon Festival</div>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>What I really looked forward to was the performance of <strong>BAND-MAID</strong>.
The timetable seemed to have a 10-minute block for the band, but the gig almost took 25 minutes.
I only know the band for a short period, but really fell in love with some of their songs.
Their performance blew me away.
I was certainly satisfied and glad I had seen them performing live.
Their genre ranges from hard rock to heavy metal but some elements make the band stand out.
First of all, all the band members are girls, which I have rarely encountered until now.
But what draws the most attention are their maid dresses.
People who are familiar with maid café's will recognise where the inspiration came from.
Two band members happen to be former maids in one of the countless maid café's in Akihabara.
During the gig, one of the two vocalists did the well known 'moe moe kyun' scene with us.
I found a video starting from the 'moe moe kyun' moment and the second part of their performance.
Due to the volume, the recording doesn&#8217;t sound great, but it gives you a good idea of how the band looks like.</p>
</div>
<div class="videoblock">
<div class="content">
<iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/pbCfuKlAtkk?rel=0&amp;hl=jp" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>
</div>
</div>
<div id="img-bandmaid" class="imageblock">
<div class="content">
<img src="https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/hYBBm_6igadHDsxxTcxcra6ROTcPmvbQ7gNR_rwqKMRf9tkLA3s1s4aKfTYMhB2-WiJuHI3C7wINh_V_41CbDMYqcXMadM_TxvWDZCgyLMRjkk4l4QOSdLfbFqO7nLaLYZaAGnDCDAp3hZbQfICZFSIrsHVZ73kS0L_ktv5QBocc4MGgJ-OMe-AtOv5Rr9HPS6Kn0U-6ySnMOjjVbESq7_OoFLT0zVQm4Ds8kp5xaJsnkliUExU-abYk5dD89LPd2tLxfP4qVYwVTT_urUtkbAxC3VDn0-x_AB5P9PWXizTE0phwrQsZwuSEZXTAlq9iF7TjKvcybZ0XAWbxY0LBMjtOou7J3iav9bN8paNzaDbkQW2hDa8iPPapN4QEnBB0kCV0Bnk0koajQfDCj5SfpcaadLpVjgaJqWkLQ8U7O36iGEzQeuFjUssLJ1TaWABlbS1Damb19HneLZ2EM4M_FdotS0xAoFATuMhBSCi3Fh9KB-E7m-fkhw4_4r08hrC3LdiBIurswlOs1IwB_KC7TuG5x8aoYUnJ1xAleWln8rTxiZN_gNE-hb4JrpbmJ0dyBiyruBtYrc479HuVMFToBIra4S_6acsGJrJKHFh4q3YBsQxlig-shENnZ65vNr6FtIW2aKhl6WUnjsU9TwQ4DM8vGhAe4KHPRFym2_v0lw=w950-h713-no" alt="hYBBm 6igadHDsxxTcxcra6ROTcPmvbQ7gNR rwqKMRf9tkLA3s1s4aKfTYMhB2 WiJuHI3C7wINh V 41CbDMYqcXMadM TxvWDZCgyLMRjkk4l4QOSdLfbFqO7nLaLYZaAGnDCDAp3hZbQfICZFSIrsHVZ73kS0L ktv5QBocc4MGgJ OMe AtOv5Rr9HPS6Kn0U 6ySnMOjjVbESq7 OoFLT0zVQm4Ds8kp5xaJsnkliUExU abYk5dD89LPd2tLxfP4qVYwVTT urUtkbAxC3VDn0 x AB5P9PWXizTE0phwrQsZwuSEZXTAlq9iF7TjKvcybZ0XAWbxY0LBMjtOou7J3iav9bN8paNzaDbkQW2hDa8iPPapN4QEnBB0kCV0Bnk0koajQfDCj5SfpcaadLpVjgaJqWkLQ8U7O36iGEzQeuFjUssLJ1TaWABlbS1Damb19HneLZ2EM4M FdotS0xAoFATuMhBSCi3Fh9KB E7m fkhw4 4r08hrC3LdiBIurswlOs1IwB KC7TuG5x8aoYUnJ1xAleWln8rTxiZN gNE hb4JrpbmJ0dyBiyruBtYrc479HuVMFToBIra4S 6acsGJrJKHFh4q3YBsQxlig shENnZ65vNr6FtIW2aKhl6WUnjsU9TwQ4DM8vGhAe4KHPRFym2 v0lw=w950 h713 no">
</div>
<div class="title">Figure 2. The best picture I could take of the BAND-MAID performance</div>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Outside the venue, I saw a performance of <strong>Niji no Conquistador</strong>, an idol group with quite young girls. I haven&#8217;t checked their actual ages, but I had the impression they were around 14 to 16.
Their fanclub was clearly present in the crowd, throwing in all their screams, jumps, even one guy stood (litterly standing on his feet straight up) on top of another guy cheering for the idols.
Really funny and impressive to see how these fanatic fans give the fullest of themselves during the performance.
I ended the festival with the performance of <strong>Silent Siren</strong>, another all-female band in a more pop rock style of music.
It was also a really amazing performance!
In front of me there was another genki fanatic cheerer who almost broke the camera of his neighbour when he was throwing his fist in the air and jumping around.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>During November, I also had some cultural events at/with school.
On an afternoon, there was a calligraphy session.
I tried at least 20 times to draw the Kanji for heart (心, kokoro), but it didn&#8217;t turn out the way I wanted to.
I blame the brush!
It was way more difficult then I thought to draw the strokes the way they should be.
It demands a lot of attention and patience, which I didn&#8217;t have that day for unknown reasons.</p>
</div>
<div id="img-z" class="imageblock">
<div class="content">
<img src="https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/ufvPZh2peSrC_CheBfczPToAw_XWns32aVdjeu47LVjeW2JjVVzpS_QRn2yVlhf0mbX4dGu4N7I1GRIY_mOZepSEUujeU4OCVtNNEH8CfD61bEyGdh5Pv-aEFNi_KeOscd66uau-g1Lr7jYgoVhctq_22KhzLttcFuQXPEtnetsf-oW14gmHY5cEPuXnXICfS1m5jbcniwcHIvLwGVk_h8duPferwzHutxkMuWbaH8ZAfpemffSb0gRelIBvhaIxrDyva5tESc2cDNav7syp0653Lun6ZD5rnvYZcOOr4A007Ua_7rfN11VfAEYDcFqZk5sH_Dim93NOPkA_sbN4DM0xm85IgzGGABT-8o3KvS3x-7Dst3GG0u3ez6l3LwquYmWbn8rsDCh0yRCc403pkHWi9OGPx-KDvOE2qgSz1TnGSzB7hYZqI17o9lCHHtUIQHiWshXpNrVwrX9KCVfuRVsH4Ibg8PBMktwumsk4n8Ucc_vFUHWhLxmPNfvOXGFkzTZg3AHmau-r7EiWz3X4JrjzCO00FXt0gOW1oWi7R9JJ2VtbkWzW97GjhVo8WQZJ91xBbJgxl_6CfNsbCcZ3UyKzBY-33ms_OSkdVJnQFv0MwrGAcbOGjwHGjVRQPvXRL02bbyG_w5ia2_df5QkGAO1tWlx6an_ictWk7t70lg=w713-h950-no" alt="ufvPZh2peSrC CheBfczPToAw XWns32aVdjeu47LVjeW2JjVVzpS QRn2yVlhf0mbX4dGu4N7I1GRIY mOZepSEUujeU4OCVtNNEH8CfD61bEyGdh5Pv aEFNi KeOscd66uau g1Lr7jYgoVhctq 22KhzLttcFuQXPEtnetsf oW14gmHY5cEPuXnXICfS1m5jbcniwcHIvLwGVk h8duPferwzHutxkMuWbaH8ZAfpemffSb0gRelIBvhaIxrDyva5tESc2cDNav7syp0653Lun6ZD5rnvYZcOOr4A007Ua 7rfN11VfAEYDcFqZk5sH Dim93NOPkA sbN4DM0xm85IgzGGABT 8o3KvS3x 7Dst3GG0u3ez6l3LwquYmWbn8rsDCh0yRCc403pkHWi9OGPx KDvOE2qgSz1TnGSzB7hYZqI17o9lCHHtUIQHiWshXpNrVwrX9KCVfuRVsH4Ibg8PBMktwumsk4n8Ucc vFUHWhLxmPNfvOXGFkzTZg3AHmau r7EiWz3X4JrjzCO00FXt0gOW1oWi7R9JJ2VtbkWzW97GjhVo8WQZJ91xBbJgxl 6CfNsbCcZ3UyKzBY 33ms OSkdVJnQFv0MwrGAcbOGjwHGjVRQPvXRL02bbyG w5ia2 df5QkGAO1tWlx6an ictWk7t70lg=w713 h950 no">
</div>
<div class="title">Figure 3. My final calligraphy drawing</div>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>In the same week, we also had a school trip to the <a href="http://tatemonoen.jp/english/"><strong>Edo-Tokyo Open Air Architectural Museum</strong></a>.
Belgian folks can compare this museum to Bokrijk.
The museum consists of old buildings, like houses, shops, farms etc. from the Edo period.
There was even an old style onsen.
The visit was finished by a traditional Japanese tea ceremony (茶道, saado).
The day before the ceremony, we learned the proper etiquette during the ceremony.
Being scared to forget some of the steps of the ceremony, I was really nervous, since I didn&#8217;t want to ruin the ceremony by making any mistake.
Next to this, the blood circulation in my legs decided to give up after sitting quite a long time on my knees, which became really painful.
But in the end, it was a nice experience.
To finally end this blog, I share with you the small number of pictures I have from the Museum and the tea ceremony.</p>
</div>
<div id="img-daibutsu" class="imageblock">
<div class="content">
<img src="https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/P4aCtN2VO4Xu1rkqlwQUi6k9avxtdHBojGkHT5TtV_MhIEohrA6SzwBEtyKkcaE1_cipzw_1auCwTQRITWc_hx-lWWeS7KeruUDTPxUA_jdjf9RX7pdGyeDK3SBYpOem8qL11xGvSlsZn_rCPZ69HG5u2gIaGOxFLqc81lbh1-czuh2zOTb61zmlIhlqtht9BWS3KzeAl3e_L6mK548BvxRCPH1uWBj-ZfUjG7a33f2KbctSWiXeuttb2iwmSr7JSvTtWUW8BHIhrEPd8LvUzjF8uOSWMc-6kc7yxsv0D9NHHud9lLPpsKj2JrQ7Qcj7fa5cTrhkKDWFkzZ5eaLnhwSompvHWsj1E8bg7aywUMhodR_LT6oUER270hDd7cGfRd6gNf8A2qv2Ak3NLsV_DoexusGhFSDqAnRJo8USNomNsfLCXncLDp-eQ0zUTIo9ZBImeSCzxXHZsQsLlRGIHyZkRu-29chE2Zp-dnjEv4ySZ9wCds3iZdFrHXlg8NBxYUhFET47OS7ZhdDEtktPkiiXx_WMQlKp14U6hPY1dJH9z9iv0Y6CeIuAIS_SYWt_2ixKkZ8uHtiIuZn21b52ZzAFhiCFNsHrJA7Wmj6jSfAr14iCEgPzoKycFqdN_BeX1h4IZTIrbfVQsEWbE-B8uqXBD40XxWjP2TAjoeH7HA=w698-h930-no" alt="P4aCtN2VO4Xu1rkqlwQUi6k9avxtdHBojGkHT5TtV MhIEohrA6SzwBEtyKkcaE1 cipzw 1auCwTQRITWc hx lWWeS7KeruUDTPxUA jdjf9RX7pdGyeDK3SBYpOem8qL11xGvSlsZn rCPZ69HG5u2gIaGOxFLqc81lbh1 czuh2zOTb61zmlIhlqtht9BWS3KzeAl3e L6mK548BvxRCPH1uWBj ZfUjG7a33f2KbctSWiXeuttb2iwmSr7JSvTtWUW8BHIhrEPd8LvUzjF8uOSWMc 6kc7yxsv0D9NHHud9lLPpsKj2JrQ7Qcj7fa5cTrhkKDWFkzZ5eaLnhwSompvHWsj1E8bg7aywUMhodR LT6oUER270hDd7cGfRd6gNf8A2qv2Ak3NLsV DoexusGhFSDqAnRJo8USNomNsfLCXncLDp eQ0zUTIo9ZBImeSCzxXHZsQsLlRGIHyZkRu 29chE2Zp dnjEv4ySZ9wCds3iZdFrHXlg8NBxYUhFET47OS7ZhdDEtktPkiiXx WMQlKp14U6hPY1dJH9z9iv0Y6CeIuAIS SYWt 2ixKkZ8uHtiIuZn21b52ZzAFhiCFNsHrJA7Wmj6jSfAr14iCEgPzoKycFqdN BeX1h4IZTIrbfVQsEWbE B8uqXBD40XxWjP2TAjoeH7HA=w698 h930 no">
</div>
<div class="title">Figure 4. After the tea ceremony we had the oportunity to pose with the equipment</div>
</div>
<div id="img-u" class="imageblock">
<div class="content">
<img src="https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/_JGAfnsdli8EDcfBG_dx5gcIOK5-r4HLaRPEmn9p8K541pO80SXf9KLAZ0ZO2jiAsEdWHih3ltfKMEP_Rc5kAq2e0KO35a6_C0al2yujUxfwxd5t3-Is32_AP5jSrUDURW8oAC7KfuG7YfMmZkYSxhunRSODXv2IvW28TSJQNlN2gQEs2u1AlDU_vdq5f_h7GS0tDSk9JRET6qRk-3cw1j14VeDmt2DZlQaqZlKAYlxEMFMYcDaLSbv2Het_UdSjLXovZ-Z5aQMuutSkfNEsED1ILATOWJhuJdF4v9pY1N4OWX5sK7Yzf50UVm8baX4UJW0Jk9eoOxmPb2QbGYodgKJVpjUVFrhKfGmzgeLOJcNQvmJQQbBa2t2lBFAg6KqaR37u-24jbOI8W9sOK1C3RSF2nKHOpQtwvr0E8WCCxLKWGrgzAhYWb4JqztCt0srVRYUNqoBnZA2wLWxGslOLb0aptYCID2i81w_yFkpxPmt5TMfAAFQr46f8Mio3tWeCwixVrm2cE36k-wP8R9d8Sd4RcH8COPGJZ7ttYEoOp7IZb6WJNdzxwEU8v9vduKqokm6UkTU8_mv67I005vk50QaMaG6f1gfUu-zc5gZHbVafy9efUiSj_2zBuSxCW1wxYuIjbbkFd4QZrxanFxtU2hb74UCXC_vvmtGJKp3YUg=w950-h713-no" alt=" JGAfnsdli8EDcfBG dx5gcIOK5 r4HLaRPEmn9p8K541pO80SXf9KLAZ0ZO2jiAsEdWHih3ltfKMEP Rc5kAq2e0KO35a6 C0al2yujUxfwxd5t3 Is32 AP5jSrUDURW8oAC7KfuG7YfMmZkYSxhunRSODXv2IvW28TSJQNlN2gQEs2u1AlDU vdq5f h7GS0tDSk9JRET6qRk 3cw1j14VeDmt2DZlQaqZlKAYlxEMFMYcDaLSbv2Het UdSjLXovZ Z5aQMuutSkfNEsED1ILATOWJhuJdF4v9pY1N4OWX5sK7Yzf50UVm8baX4UJW0Jk9eoOxmPb2QbGYodgKJVpjUVFrhKfGmzgeLOJcNQvmJQQbBa2t2lBFAg6KqaR37u 24jbOI8W9sOK1C3RSF2nKHOpQtwvr0E8WCCxLKWGrgzAhYWb4JqztCt0srVRYUNqoBnZA2wLWxGslOLb0aptYCID2i81w yFkpxPmt5TMfAAFQr46f8Mio3tWeCwixVrm2cE36k wP8R9d8Sd4RcH8COPGJZ7ttYEoOp7IZb6WJNdzxwEU8v9vduKqokm6UkTU8 mv67I005vk50QaMaG6f1gfUu zc5gZHbVafy9efUiSj 2zBuSxCW1wxYuIjbbkFd4QZrxanFxtU2hb74UCXC vvmtGJKp3YUg=w950 h713 no">
</div>
<div class="title">Figure 5. Close-up of the equipment</div>
</div>
<div id="img-y" class="imageblock">
<div class="content">
<img src="https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/mGDjDGGt7mMoAXCuGGb8O3z2PiU_k_VdV-sfjZhpQvKQ1hjxhK-QPmpl45ajjs27eXCXzX5hH0mLqdEReNloyJl3hHWwg9iBYzJS9WGx466nD6ylx0pEpstJ9mT0wXQFYv6gDw4fFYTiCJmL6YYoKUYr7CyroOcjr3_0ORgUdJqAslLUuWRfALoO6fdZ-yJDzGAyciyoJKUnqyYyAO0bQ9wPDvyv1SCtGGQoxixEKLuupOElz_CyxEyKrpzooaKRVgau9nNmlkxGKyRnLBaYkfqlWC3tkfwI5UBxWQSGwzi8KRMAaPHH3lgulLCglPc4wTaL8nD9Vn-rbEIQ4_W80aMlkH7LdNC0FMd9hmgw3LCACFoj4VEGEsAtHaI5oxTtF_kbrWvyV9y_OM1T4aEECsXbq9B6QsAsX962uXZNQ6BktW9YRSUoWSXs2U6TL69oWvgc4IXlnIYWhvLSgAV77f4cJn5b50LlCDjO7CwzaN0AKuat3rCFHCE6HeK_AUaZsWvoUGq_6fALqi7OEEWEZ_sgw7b7h1_qp54xkWDMpg7sNA_hVMAb-WvMNFfcGgbc8cjO5tb_HRbeyyEXQ9AJbEbbPBPyMVLLY-bxI7L2Cdw97zXicX4TQbNf5qt6LaT55My1BNHDbvvGf9czGeWWBKzxUilG-wMItpEzVpNq9Q=w950-h713-no" alt="mGDjDGGt7mMoAXCuGGb8O3z2PiU k VdV sfjZhpQvKQ1hjxhK QPmpl45ajjs27eXCXzX5hH0mLqdEReNloyJl3hHWwg9iBYzJS9WGx466nD6ylx0pEpstJ9mT0wXQFYv6gDw4fFYTiCJmL6YYoKUYr7CyroOcjr3 0ORgUdJqAslLUuWRfALoO6fdZ yJDzGAyciyoJKUnqyYyAO0bQ9wPDvyv1SCtGGQoxixEKLuupOElz CyxEyKrpzooaKRVgau9nNmlkxGKyRnLBaYkfqlWC3tkfwI5UBxWQSGwzi8KRMAaPHH3lgulLCglPc4wTaL8nD9Vn rbEIQ4 W80aMlkH7LdNC0FMd9hmgw3LCACFoj4VEGEsAtHaI5oxTtF kbrWvyV9y OM1T4aEECsXbq9B6QsAsX962uXZNQ6BktW9YRSUoWSXs2U6TL69oWvgc4IXlnIYWhvLSgAV77f4cJn5b50LlCDjO7CwzaN0AKuat3rCFHCE6HeK AUaZsWvoUGq 6fALqi7OEEWEZ sgw7b7h1 qp54xkWDMpg7sNA hVMAb WvMNFfcGgbc8cjO5tb HRbeyyEXQ9AJbEbbPBPyMVLLY bxI7L2Cdw97zXicX4TQbNf5qt6LaT55My1BNHDbvvGf9czGeWWBKzxUilG wMItpEzVpNq9Q=w950 h713 no">
</div>
<div class="title">Figure 6. Inside the onsen</div>
</div>
<div id="img-x" class="imageblock">
<div class="content">
<img src="https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/RJ_vOFh5s3433yJB0fFMFfhrvoWVGfuybnBweElp35sDzBwNtjQEAut4Qy_NLi4BNRMeE2ekVOhP4MNwrpkyYyr7AIirtr5UhrJK6j8YxXtx8iFUenb-LCRAX4cyyPv-XPfQeoycVSWMymwSVQ3avL9ukhLTuIwh_qf1meBn2gapTDwnVRyBJHtcFEgBcVs8AMWydzm4kxOvM2bEsZlW1iTqgNWC0Hmiw4_zQobZGHUXT3ZvVNL6dD-4KCMXdwWL9-o0Zbjj6dV2DD6kVHkjh0H0DUQckCyBObrCbtB--blmx6YSiFTkiX_wwAMEJju-Vcbk1ZB0-s92NK9l1sJKOjL_GGFU3zkXJzcHzHkVPezfFE9nHnPlpYnhMuHQ32R9OIoipoaqbfdIfatrtDZDyd4hlgcIgc5nSpJNHMwxiJx27SX54lLBL-RTHoep13XoAOKtToWsrhN9hzjp0c5-4tjvojwY1Xz0jfcW5mEadEQ45-eipyucWSwWvAupPG7CSeUyvzSDR7nqMl_T7x7K5dF28YSPLbQlPYmo9vlQXxh4Lqd0ezLVj3k5nAhHF7OK7GCvMDWWOr54GOzAhsNmJOGAkwvSkmHX90SFSvKF5XRQ0crtKmqHT7W-PGNgpmuPbMMNAuQrMP9VkOsLAdsdbC7l7AJ7H52NfaMsro7VXQ=w950-h713-no" alt="RJ vOFh5s3433yJB0fFMFfhrvoWVGfuybnBweElp35sDzBwNtjQEAut4Qy NLi4BNRMeE2ekVOhP4MNwrpkyYyr7AIirtr5UhrJK6j8YxXtx8iFUenb LCRAX4cyyPv XPfQeoycVSWMymwSVQ3avL9ukhLTuIwh qf1meBn2gapTDwnVRyBJHtcFEgBcVs8AMWydzm4kxOvM2bEsZlW1iTqgNWC0Hmiw4 zQobZGHUXT3ZvVNL6dD 4KCMXdwWL9 o0Zbjj6dV2DD6kVHkjh0H0DUQckCyBObrCbtB  blmx6YSiFTkiX wwAMEJju Vcbk1ZB0 s92NK9l1sJKOjL GGFU3zkXJzcHzHkVPezfFE9nHnPlpYnhMuHQ32R9OIoipoaqbfdIfatrtDZDyd4hlgcIgc5nSpJNHMwxiJx27SX54lLBL RTHoep13XoAOKtToWsrhN9hzjp0c5 4tjvojwY1Xz0jfcW5mEadEQ45 eipyucWSwWvAupPG7CSeUyvzSDR7nqMl T7x7K5dF28YSPLbQlPYmo9vlQXxh4Lqd0ezLVj3k5nAhHF7OK7GCvMDWWOr54GOzAhsNmJOGAkwvSkmHX90SFSvKF5XRQ0crtKmqHT7W PGNgpmuPbMMNAuQrMP9VkOsLAdsdbC7l7AJ7H52NfaMsro7VXQ=w950 h713 no">
</div>
<div class="title">Figure 7. A small mausoleum</div>
</div>]]></description><link>https://endymion64.github.io/2016/12/08/November-Update.html</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://endymion64.github.io/2016/12/08/November-Update.html</guid><pubDate>Thu, 08 Dec 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Kamakura]]></title><description><![CDATA[<div class="paragraph">
<p>Let&#8217;s tell a bit about the places I have visited! I have walked through several parks in  Tokyo, made a stop at the Pokémon Center in Ikebukoro and wandered around in Akihabara drooling on all the anime merchandise I saw over there! That&#8217;s only the tip of the iceberg of what I have done, but I still need to explore a lot of Tokyo. I guess I will get the opportunity to do this during the Christmas break. Last month I even left Tokyo to visit the beatiful city Kamakura (鎌倉) with 3 other Vulcanus trainees. The city is only 50 kilometers south from Tokyo and has a long history, which makes it an attractive spot for tourists.
What can you expect to find in Kamakura? Well, it&#8217;s very simple: religious spots, tons and tons of them. The city is surrounded by Shinto shrines (神社：じんじゃ; jinja) and Buddhist temples (お寺：おてら; otera). Some of them were built centuries ago and still remain.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>We made a nice roundtrip around the city and witnessed a rather green village without skyscapers, which really contrasts with the Tokyo Metropolitan Area. I felt a bit relieved actually to be out of the big city for a bit. Since it is way more interesting to see for yourself where I have been, I decided to make this post more interactive by adding a map of my roundtrip. We had a nice walk of around 10km, starting from Kamakura station and ending at Kita-Kamakura station. Of course, I also took some pictures. I&#8217;m not going to waste a lot of words in this post and let the map and pictures speak for themselves: <a href="https://goo.gl/photos/G2qetVywN4awRXzq5"><strong>ALBUM</strong></a></p>
</div>
<style>
    .google-maps {
        position: relative;
        padding-bottom: 75%; // This is the aspect ratio
        height: 0;
        overflow: hidden;
    }
    .google-maps iframe {
        position: absolute;
        top: 0;
        left: 0;
        width: 100% !important;
        height: 100% !important;
    }
</style>

<div class="google-maps">
<iframe src="https://www.google.com/maps/d/embed?mid=1ich19Hjatxr5G3xoG0cAjqbUIn0" width="640" height="480" frameborder="0" style="border:0"></iframe>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Our first stop was the village&#8217;s most famous attraction: the great Buddha Statue, a.k.a Daibutsu (大仏, Big Buddha). It&#8217;s a 13,35 meters high sitting Buddha made out of bronze and was built in the 13th century! It&#8217;s set in the middle of a Buddhist temple and it is even possible to enter the insides of the statues.</p>
</div>
<div id="img-daibutsu" class="imageblock">
<div class="content">
<img src="https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/kiPrNwTGiaKTkbAHdztH0AEXhwZiqpIxorv6VOqvXWWHT8zMklea80Wgqoyze3jDNjwepQ6YOu5RoywapiOqzdNYa9f7Psxi-oPcNa4AfWzWB_Xv2X2ITTIMS0OCN_JRUOB3B6lWUyiQC1r5vJljkoab8eK9zbqBJhT8PAo9w0_DYYR46_pBqhYxRUTrgC8egrliYrN8Eiv70iYeisEfWhSEUVFZJhPhtKXpf47NaxMMl4ictqEZ7y-eXXgTmXGAv7QCCCa-CltIeOlmSFAdfsV3mbGHcyXFfF-j9MNEmXNalEbnywS0iIldH-864n6owcbR6Zj-a8-HIUnM2nudvf2XB4hdI-6KIbOZa_FvYBb83cnqJIy0j7B4VbqH1Q2aD017oxqACiXiysjWjzwm4MdM2tVfrEXZBSPYlqAtnZPY0sawMscZQDe11DMHYn13CiPOENnr-LOSo1aOtOoqEz37GFXECN0hSFFTsC4u_t5f2ZirHwM9bEzOcvyuwbV1YfMA3lkQdmrMVi2tmGZBASMoX6XB0JFjb342tEyWHD5P-DE6r3rt8X2Wb3of8fbO55tVPqDSUrg9Cq_7dKVpiIHRwfxBMCvpgJJtk3zGafHjosui=w620-h930-no" alt="Daibutsu">
</div>
<div class="title">Figure 1. Big Boy Buddha</div>
</div>
<div id="img-innerbuddha" class="imageblock">
<div class="content">
<img src="https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/TK6_SUZyHmUtfnNsuFizeV5shVrmYxbiUI-GRagpnX_NwV5LxzsVS9XfV4hASfARMbatw38b9KWtFrtopF9VIWD4t9bM3THP6f6gq2_3RX8o7OW3R_p1yUux9a5nYREE1abQWKk7rSVeuNzrW6CpnRhQ7XvT_vsY1HV_vFaVmjY66B4IzC3H-xTlr1a39hadGJaGLljStiCXbkgDa2KO-HSPBCNZ5i45FpU6HmduW0njf8IK5tilkzndUzWrn6gHY3XxMoqQUHzdGoehPgloweW46qZGnWh1uGVr12hS71uIuprB-z_AzwP-FPhtWN0TivNPWmcKp92giyPtGqnNiMh6ffoa3E5XLhMSdD8McJTOL_RWPamCGKMKgmYQM0IIFH_o_Wy8RuFEUTeFUrmZ06B41uLwHjSDZnDrUFbQvB0s1lbo8ImTAg3n5mKEK5NuTJjFHlGhb17YbcEwlM_rMBdRFmwlUyLqO9o5HYne4-bN9gtS0rLugaMZv_jEm1NeZF5atjATk74g-htVehiICsE37kJ6j4gk3en9mcPb0ZZtQ_rkZZIriMYn76AXVxPptBt5qu2EF7k59KIQRSJZR_JkrJ_0gZcGHdBtMXi0bnkFWtN_=w698-h930-no" alt="Inside the Daibutsu">
</div>
<div class="title">Figure 2. Inside the Daibutsu</div>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Our second stop was Hase-dera, another Buddhist Temple, built on the side of a steep hill. It is a big temple with a lot of beautiful things that turn you speechless! You can climb a lot of stairs, which grants you a nice overview over the city. You can see eagles circling around Kamakura and see the nearby beach.</p>
</div>
<div id="img-hase-dare" class="imageblock">
<div class="content">
<img src="https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/J6spejxUoL7QdPDIzF7fAYWmmMZavUA_4Emd100COSP8QhvPZnwAsmOPQswA_DWtJCkaK4T8crqvlMOVzborPHa8WkJAIhPyqQpNYyFMHQTyJJ7FzUUDJ1W3BFHpgDTEoTslo1VtiZoGitUkg_AXabQQW8SwXe0weZJ-eEdT0zUm3IuVUwUv3XjegoN-85jP3QFSNiBhMPyKQnDWRg6gGa4DsA1nPVKhec8jQgxa2lOhtLMm4Qp8sRx0UwY1u4paGrIkrTL4DYatrajbFohYIprj77OrxoeveebzrMboWOUZ04v3drk83icxvAuz-_a6iBmaru6fJ71pVAZ_U7-jU4ElgqWzLzjRHfk625MF0IDocVMw6gklUN0KyD97HlES_xYlKFRZarVjGMiajCq2Nih6dqMhSdz6aqZrihgykS6hNMREal6KHEek5rTaMUPzqxmpH68L-CPW93lYxg9x70ABW75C-_ndWjqEN0GNvG_qb2H0S2rkcktZI3ylcXuh0EW1TzHnmGJSdvsVIZDO-MRo2xJuaG2Qm7zEQ2SLyeujppxaYy3x0Lk-X1GtqIwk1GVxCUYyP0IUK-xvmhGtDBeZqKii0y08XL-l0YTkUjlMCssP=w1240-h930-no" alt="hase-dare">
</div>
<div class="title">Figure 3. One of the amazing sightings at Hase-dare</div>
</div>
<div id="hase-dare-view" class="imageblock">
<div class="content">
<img src="https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/v8CnGwn93Cwf4_c6pQpOPLCp9e7n2xlM2iW_wQZSHQvWgVI8TspvTEoTXnzmplYAF9okGDRAPRiKbuj0Cr-W-sTyJ_PgjKaPYg1nIX2fBHtbxzTA7qektFo-_2BOnOfRccr4APrUvQIOPV7QayaSAUNQW7MRy5K2s9GnjL3R-8qIvhQy-fmJDV3709UWG_a1Ot9h3ZDikgcnf79Qv4mkuNQ8d9eQtpH1libhjPwI3SfZMgqDtff73ouuBiroWizfTX901aI1JKT11djyWb7WNM4cnl6Z9L7FBzQzuMngzyBBkpIZbKxghB4wrJdQqRgNxlXv8WP1_azXUbrKmRZwdwMS9Zb2_7V8Q9QhUAgzfCte63QbsLN2UlFeWbXKYCW7KTgET550VgfuFbgvccClEe_aqPh6yIYOqyOU0DzYsQUDoOvlieLAlT-bT021QxWzwwwl_iIAipGkZyD6B6NnIGJq4G7yNRfHRIQ3GA1aXQvL7Axyd27H1QHjPtFVKT91OpsTnySllY4EFk9tSnkZKlOk1Qz9Fx0Vvp1BEWhjDOHuSEJYD48fwZTwab7hz38joRvoGCirGQpItiNKu46oVjwD0bwCtriB4JYaZCzdNThkyYYD=w1240-h930-no" alt="v8CnGwn93Cwf4 c6pQpOPLCp9e7n2xlM2iW wQZSHQvWgVI8TspvTEoTXnzmplYAF9okGDRAPRiKbuj0Cr W sTyJ PgjKaPYg1nIX2fBHtbxzTA7qektFo  2BOnOfRccr4APrUvQIOPV7QayaSAUNQW7MRy5K2s9GnjL3R 8qIvhQy fmJDV3709UWG a1Ot9h3ZDikgcnf79Qv4mkuNQ8d9eQtpH1libhjPwI3SfZMgqDtff73ouuBiroWizfTX901aI1JKT11djyWb7WNM4cnl6Z9L7FBzQzuMngzyBBkpIZbKxghB4wrJdQqRgNxlXv8WP1 azXUbrKmRZwdwMS9Zb2 7V8Q9QhUAgzfCte63QbsLN2UlFeWbXKYCW7KTgET550VgfuFbgvccClEe aqPh6yIYOqyOU0DzYsQUDoOvlieLAlT bT021QxWzwwwl iIAipGkZyD6B6NnIGJq4G7yNRfHRIQ3GA1aXQvL7Axyd27H1QHjPtFVKT91OpsTnySllY4EFk9tSnkZKlOk1Qz9Fx0Vvp1BEWhjDOHuSEJYD48fwZTwab7hz38joRvoGCirGQpItiNKu46oVjwD0bwCtriB4JYaZCzdNThkyYYD=w1240 h930 no">
</div>
<div class="title">Figure 4. View from up the Hase-dare</div>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Did I just say beach? Yes, there is one! That was our third stop: walking on the beach and touching Japanese sea water for the first time in forever! (yes, this was an intended cross reference to a Disney movie)</p>
</div>
<div id="beach" class="imageblock">
<div class="content">
<img src="https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/0Psx8Ln8D7ro6SlqA7kLQXQ_CNNLo57Sjbr-e4-ZES44982G1td5_v8X85NlJYT8VeVRQKIQ_95jwahwsYSMQZTPfow72IEkzUigIsdnSbNESKNVJrLAivOlfaiRP0kTj6Mia86x5Giq9Rz4xZgzdnMNfIKo3H7AIlMphdQ_SFUqumEWHWuL_Ya3F_sr8JRYLM_oMdPfN_XpyQajc02OkfR8hxqZGCA3PKJI3EcOk9qgWcDXtQnNAXPnMbLq9ODp3mRwnFa07Yo-dsyqlR3UjKaA_9dGZD7581vfB0piLpLpwqv7kcszaGFuhoI8FwSCKgLGxZGNG0CzkA1Q_mHrJ9poJf7a0s9XLubn9EWqhhivl9ElCz5RsdKGJOoGySffULGP0KtQLMYXBqjHHcXsAFZkBRLLhRi7Z-Hmrw9rIBe6lTTP6HYYQL33Kvem3FoouTqPm-_LU9o3LwEBa-Gw409mZgfZhRI08gCQumN8hB4BeBGBcRUlJ1aR_xYH8iSKitSuyay5qD38Gf_cKIM8zmn52wX0cH2DA-R8UvQdjYJJWacYZMZ_yZGIgO0VFYV_eLldB5G5X6nU0bZRag4757L84ZBlGjHglp1U8NESnxzF_fnX=w1240-h930-no" alt="0Psx8Ln8D7ro6SlqA7kLQXQ CNNLo57Sjbr e4 ZES44982G1td5 v8X85NlJYT8VeVRQKIQ 95jwahwsYSMQZTPfow72IEkzUigIsdnSbNESKNVJrLAivOlfaiRP0kTj6Mia86x5Giq9Rz4xZgzdnMNfIKo3H7AIlMphdQ SFUqumEWHWuL Ya3F sr8JRYLM oMdPfN XpyQajc02OkfR8hxqZGCA3PKJI3EcOk9qgWcDXtQnNAXPnMbLq9ODp3mRwnFa07Yo dsyqlR3UjKaA 9dGZD7581vfB0piLpLpwqv7kcszaGFuhoI8FwSCKgLGxZGNG0CzkA1Q mHrJ9poJf7a0s9XLubn9EWqhhivl9ElCz5RsdKGJOoGySffULGP0KtQLMYXBqjHHcXsAFZkBRLLhRi7Z Hmrw9rIBe6lTTP6HYYQL33Kvem3FoouTqPm  LU9o3LwEBa Gw409mZgfZhRI08gCQumN8hB4BeBGBcRUlJ1aR xYH8iSKitSuyay5qD38Gf cKIM8zmn52wX0cH2DA R8UvQdjYJJWacYZMZ yZGIgO0VFYV eLldB5G5X6nU0bZRag4757L84ZBlGjHglp1U8NESnxzF fnX=w1240 h930 no">
</div>
<div class="title">Figure 5. My first Japanese beach</div>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>After that we went for the Gyonyama Hiking Trail over one of the mountains surrounding Kamakura. There was a nice lookout point on the route, giving you a nice view of the village from the west side. The trail brought us to the biggest Shinto shrine of Kamakura: Tsurugaoka Hachiman-gū, where I was pleased to witness a Shinto wedding ceremony!</p>
</div>
<div id="img-kekkonshiki" class="imageblock">
<div class="content">
<img src="https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/g4agqHTMVyKoCWaKn2whfy4Cx2YeQJq7NhHyGva1Q_G1aeYwzfhul9KLEABBzguTPPdDmL0O9IP8XomEuGfq9lUBenr8V8EbQ7m6WyDw7gR6JV6UIN7__BEQIJVMsHvALxOcE4Qu9IA5SLTM_YYjcSF52PJqlU18dzCmFulcFXImjnVATV8NTqvnAgty-UOFee_CTTaAI4xupx1-cLDMjpUKnLoLhb-dN7zsHsiVmp_w1h_PjGqz8MKNcG-po6tLQOwo8EqnBkpOWINnnM0N9hIaIZJRotaABTF9AIcfbjW1Jku9Zyk2Nw0majsPsC-gMzvD6MuthpPsLRhe5a_g-WawsXRPQgE66v2168RK740JfELcRR7ydikvME_8-pS0OckzTGvKehqSRYoV68DBGTCAtvSjGkSU03hfqqOcENDVS1A41-WC28hsxeMn0rz6oD-bZH2gNe5BovcNkCMdj3-Ng61dz8Wdm-A4pGng6IZJPx9Iolh80v4tdkvJMqHHVZ3o4Dc5jEvJnQ0exw8d2gZaaKcqaKUKiG9bXPiTp39690irT1hOOF7Dc27Jh8iwPhrSpgXUc-3HU4D78N9YAi7yJSK7IjFhzBGHkayC7aGivpFD=w1240-h930-no" alt="Kekkonshiki">
</div>
<div class="title">Figure 6. The wedding ceremony in the Lower Worship Hall of Tsurugaoka Hachiman-gū</div>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>After the wedding, our journey continued through the main street for some food and then we walked all the way to Kita-Kamakura station to visit the Engaku-ji, a Buddhist Temple just besides the station. This was our final stop for this tiring but oh so satisfying trip.
I can only say I have enjoyed the day from beginning 'til the end and can only recommend people to visit the town for themselves and take the time to actually walk around! Most of the sites are close to train stations, but you will enjoy the green environment more by walking from one spot to another in my opinion. Be sure to check the remaining pictures in my <a href="https://goo.gl/photos/G2qetVywN4awRXzq5"><strong>album</strong></a>!</p>
</div>]]></description><link>https://endymion64.github.io/2016/11/03/Kamakura.html</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://endymion64.github.io/2016/11/03/Kamakura.html</guid><pubDate>Thu, 03 Nov 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Studying Japanese]]></title><description><![CDATA[<div class="paragraph">
<p>What have I been doing in Japan until now? Besides visiting some nice places and events like Akihabara, Yoyogi Park, Tokyo Game Show and Kamakura (the latter will be the topic of my next post), I&#8217;ve spent most of my time in Shibuya. Sidenote: I really recommend you to visit the <a href="https://vulcanus.stanovnik.net/"><strong>blog</strong></a> of my Slovene buddy, Sašo, for some awesome pictures of Akihabara and other places he visited (which I mostly joined) Why Shibuya? I study in a private school over there: <a href="http://www.naganuma-school.ac.jp/"><strong>The Naganuma School - Tokyo School of Japanese Language</strong></a>. What could I possibly be studying over there? It&#8217;s not Computer Science I can tell you ;)</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Before heading to Japan, there was a Vulcanus meeting near the European headquarters of the EU-Japan Centre in Brussels. At the end of the meeting, we had a small test to measure the level of Japanese we already (might have) had. This was done to select the students who already have some Japanese knowledge and put these people into special courses which are more advanced. There was made an advanced class for those trainees, the 花 (Hana, flower) class. The Japanese language knowledge of two Vulcanus trainees is so advanced, they were allowed to follow a course on 'Business Japanese'!</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>I&#8217;ve already had 7 weeks of classes. My Japanese language course will last until the mid of December. Especially for the Vulcanus students, the school took the effort to compress their initial language course to a 4-months schedule which normally takes 6-months! Of course, this means that we need to process a lot of content in less time than originally expected. This is hard for the students, but do not underestimate what this demands of the teachers too! They have to prepare their lessons faster than usual and have to be sure to stick to schedule.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>In this course, we study the two みんなの日本語 (Minna no Nihongo: literally translates to 'everyone&#8217;s Japanese') Shokyu books, consisting of 25 chapters each, guided by a grammar book. We finished the first book last week and are currently at lesson 28 (third chapter of the second book). Apart from the books, we also have lessons where we focus on pronunciation, presentation practice and Kanji reading and writing. Kanji is the Chinese writing system that was adopted centuries ago by Japan. Most of the words you see in public life are therefore written using Kanji. Besides Kanji, there is another group of characters which are called Kana: the authentic Japanese writing system which was developed after Kanji. It consists of the 2 character sets ひらがな (Hiragana) and カタカナ (Katakana). These sets both have different purposes. The main distinction you can make between Hiragana and Katakana is that the former is used for conjugations and particles, whilst the latter is used to spell foreign words in a Japanese&#8217;yfied manner. Since I only know Kana and a very, very, VERY small number of Kanji at the moment (let&#8217;s pin it to a number of 30 for now), I can barely read anything in the streets, but little by little I&#8217;m making progress!</p>
</div>
<div id="img-books" class="imageblock thumb">
<div class="content">
<img src="https://endymion64.github.io/images/school/books.jpg" alt="books">
</div>
<div class="title">Figure 1. These are all the books and work files I&#8217;ll study. On top we have the first part, in the middle my Kanji book and on the bottom we have the second part of the Minna no Nihongo books</div>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>From Monday to Friday, I commute to school. One trip from my apartment to school takes around 50 minutes and consists of approximately 2 kilometers of walking and traveling by train. This means I walk almost 4 kilometers on a daily basis, which is very good to maintain my health and weight! I currently have the goal to walk at least 8000 steps per day, which I easily manage to do now.
The 34 Vulcanus trainees are divided into smaller groups of 6 to 8 people. My class is called 星 (Hoshi: Star) and I have two main teachers 渡邉先生　(Watanabe-sensei) on Mondays and Wednesdays and 柴田先生　(Shibata-sensei) on Thursday&#8217;s. What about Tuesdays and Fridays? Well, on those days the teachers switch from classrooms by shifting either clockwise or counterclockwise. So, in total I learn Japanese from 4 different teachers. This is in my opinion a good approach, because each teacher has her (all my teachers are women) own approach and style of teaching. Next to this, it allows us to improve our listening skills since we&#8217;re confronted with different voices. All the teachers are really kind and what really impresses me is the effort they put in each lesson. They try to make each topic as attractive as possible to the students by involving their personal preferences and experiences into each conversation. Besides teaching us Japanese, they also offer help when we had some troubles that don&#8217;t consider the language class. For instance, I received a notice from Leopalace about the alarm system of my apartment. I asked Watanabe-sensei for a small summary of what was written. It said the alarm system had to be upgraded and I had to make an appointment with the security company. Since my level of Japanese speech is still far from feeling comfortable to have phone conversations, I was really glad that Watanabe-sensei spontaneously offered to make the phone call herself.</p>
</div>
<div id="img-watanabe" class="imageblock">
<div class="content">
<img src="https://endymion64.github.io/images/school/watanabe.jpg" alt="watanabe">
</div>
<div class="title">Figure 2. Watanabe-sensei, with special thanks to Sašo for shooting it</div>
</div>
<div id="img-shibata" class="imageblock">
<div class="content">
<img src="https://endymion64.github.io/images/school/shibata.jpg" alt="shibata">
</div>
<div class="title">Figure 3. Shibata-sensei, with special thanks to Mateusz Pabian for shooting it</div>
</div>
<div id="img-itou" class="imageblock">
<div class="content">
<img src="https://endymion64.github.io/images/school/itou.jpg" alt="itou">
</div>
<div class="title">Figure 4. Itou-sensei, main teacher of the Hana class who teaches us on Tuesdays. Thanks again to Mateusz for shooting it</div>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>School starts at 9 o&#8217;clock. We have school periods of 45 minutes, followed by a 10-minute-break. After 4 school periods we have lunch from 12:30 to 13:30. The number of school periods we have in the afternoon alters: normally we have 2 periods, but sometimes the final period is a private lesson for a subset of the class. It might also happen that we get an additional third school period in the afternoon, which is called 'Conversation Class'. In this class, we learn some typical vocabulary used in common situations (paying groceries, ordering food in a restaurant, booking train tickets, visiting the doctor&#8230;&#8203;). So school either ends at 14:15, 15:10 or 16:05, but in general it is 15:10. School is fun, but really intensive. I really need to stay focused all the time. Therefore I&#8217;m really longing for the breaks sometimes! A lot of vocabulary, verbs and grammatical structures are crammed daily into our heads, which is why you often have to revise the lessons in the evenings to keep up with the pace. You cannot afford yourself to run behind or you&#8217;ll start to dig a pit from which it is really hard to get out! The homework we get are mostly exercises on the previous lesson and studying new vocabulary for the upcoming lesson so that we can focus more on the new grammatical structures during the day. Below, I have added a video published by the school itself that summarises their teaching method. It takes around 40 minutes, but worth it! Be sure to put on the English subtitles! ;-)</p>
</div>
<div class="videoblock">
<div class="content">
<iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/xUVLuv2IGNQ?rel=0&amp;hl=jp" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>
</div>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>What really makes my life at school complete are the two typical elements each school has in anime: the typical Japanese school bell jingle and a roof top where you can walk around, sit on a bench and have an occasional lunch break! The school bell is a very soothing sound, which is totally different from the harsh ring in the elementary and secondary school I had. The rooftop has a small view on the buildings around the school. It is really calm over there! The perfect place to come to rest during the brain melting Japanese studies!</p>
</div>
<div class="audioblock">
<div class="content">
<audio src="https://endymion64.github.io/audio/schoolbell.mp3" controls>
Your browser does not support the audio tag.
</audio>
</div>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>In short: school is intensive but really a great experience. I still suck a bit at speaking spontaneously though, especially when I need to conjugate verbs. However, Sašo found Japanese conversation classes near our station in Kawasaki! Last week, we joined these classes and meet twice a week to improve our natural speech. We were heartily welcomed from the beginning and were immediately invited to join the Tuesday&#8217;s group for a trip to Ikuta Park to have a picnic and visit the planetarium. This way we&#8217;ll try to truly master the Japanese language!</p>
</div>]]></description><link>https://endymion64.github.io/2016/10/27/Studying-Japanese.html</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://endymion64.github.io/2016/10/27/Studying-Japanese.html</guid><pubDate>Thu, 27 Oct 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[What I like about Japan]]></title><description><![CDATA[<div id="preamble">
<div class="sectionbody">
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Being in Japan for already 40 days, I noticed a lot of stuff that makes my life pleasant. I&#8217;ll try to give a summary of some of the positive things I encountered so far. First, I also wanted to summarize the stuff I don&#8217;t like about Japan so far (and yes, there are some points you won&#8217;t like about any country), but I&#8217;ll keep that for another post, so stay tuned!</p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_public_transport">Public transport</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Most of you know the legends and fairy tales about perfect train systems on which the train never comes late: the tales are true, my friend! This is absolutely the greatest thing I have encountered so far. Being used to public transport in Belgium, especially busses, Japanese public transport is a relief! Trains arrive and leave ON TIME, and then I mean SPOT-ON! In Belgium, you have to be happy if your train only arrives 5 minutes late, which is still considered on time by the NMBS (the Belgian rail company).</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>I commute between the stations Musashi-Kosugi (near my apartment) and Shibuya (near to my school) and can choose between 4 different kinds of trains on my line: Local, Express, Limited Express and Commuter Express. Local trains (かくえきていしゃ, kakuekiteisha) stop at every station on the line and hence are the slowest ones. Shibuya is the first station on the line and Musashi-Kosugi the eleventh, so 10 stops until I reach my destination, which takes about half an hour. The Express train skips 3 to 4 stations, but the fastest trains on the line are the Limited Express and Commuter Express trains. These only stop at the greater stations where you can transfer to another line. Now of course, everyone is keen on commuting quicker, which means that a lot of people prefer the Commuter Express, especially in the morning when people have to get to work or school in time. Result: whenever I tried to take the Commuter Express in the mornings, I was literally being a sardine in a can. (Could I get some lemon and salt with that?) So I prefer taking the local train instead, which will also be crowded in the mornings, but at least you can move your arms to catch your phone and read a newspaper. Commuting time doesn&#8217;t differ that much after all in my case. I guess I can gain only 10 minutes in the morning and since I leave pretty early to school, it doesn&#8217;t really matter to me. However, in the early afternoon (let&#8217;s say 15:00) the Commuter Express really gives a benefit. Then, it only takes me 10 to 12 minutes to commute between my stations and you can sit comfortably too since it isn&#8217;t that crowded.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Next to this, there are general habits in train stations that make life easier and bearable for everyone: queueing. <strong><em>What do you mean? People actually properly stand in lines to enter the train? Can people actually behave civilized?</em></strong> EXACTLY, no fighting to get in or out of the train, people properly wait until it is their turn to get in. And not only for entering the train! In huge stations, like Shibuya, you have thousands of people transferring and commuting. Therefore, a dozen of train lines enter this station, making it a huge maze, with several floors. Having so much floors in your station means you definitely have to use escalators to get around. In Japan, there is the nice habit to keep one half of the escalator free for people who are in a hurry and therefore want to walk/run on the escalators. Of course, before you get on the escalator, you queue properly in the correct line: the line for people that run on the escalators, or the line for people that stand still on the escalator.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>And then finally the last but certainly not the least thing I like about Japanese public transport: navigation. Having huge stations means you can easily get lost. However, the signs come to a help. The stations are filled with them. And luckily: all these signs have English translations! As a foreigner this is really a relief.  You simply follow the arrows to the line or exit you want to reach and done.</p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_general_kindness">General kindness</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Whenever you enter a store, you will be greeted by most of the staff. Their smiles and bows bring you in a really happy mood. But this kindness is not only present in stores, in the stations you have the common habit not to bother each other on the trains and queue properly for escalators and entering the train wagon. Japan has a huge population, especially in Tokyo, so you have to cope with the fact that there are a lot of people around you. When you want to feel at ease, you should ensure that you let others feel at ease. The best way to deal with each other is being calm and polite. But of course, this has to come from both sides! Don&#8217;t be rude, nor stare at people! Offer your seat for the elderly! Don&#8217;t, but really, DON&#8217;T play music aloud on the train! There are headsets, so use them! Turn the ringtone of your mobile phone off.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>People also help you whenever you ask them to! Let me give you an anecdote to illustrate this: last week, I was at a おこのみやき (okonomiyaki) restaurant with the other Fujitsu boys and wanted to order a new dish that we hadn&#8217;t tried before: もんじゃやき (monjayaki). Normally, you grill/cook the dish yourself at your table, but we had no clue how to do this properly since it wasn&#8217;t exactly the same as the okonomiyaki we were used to. So we asked the waiter how to do this and he grilled it for us! He really took effort in showing it to us instead of just explaining it briefly, which I really appreciate.</p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_public_bathrooms_are_free_clean">Public bathrooms are free &amp; CLEAN</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<div class="paragraph">
<p>In Belgium, you easily pay 50 cents of 'maintenance fee' to use a public toilet and from time to time these bathrooms have a rather 'used' impression. But people in Japan have a better understanding of general hygiene in my opinion and leave the toilets behind in the way they want to encounter them: clean. So no need to pay a toilet lady that has to supervise the bathroom continuously and clean the place. Of course these toilets get properly cleaned, but at least in Japan the staff does not have to be present all the time to check whether you aim correctly or not.</p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_convenience_stores_convenience_stores_everywhere">Convenience stores, convenience stores everywhere</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<div class="paragraph">
<p>コンビニ (konbini, short for convenience store) are everywhere. For the Belgian reader, you can compare these shops to Carrefour Express or City Delhaize. Just across my apartment, there is a 7-Eleven, where I can buy warm bento&#8217;s whenever I don&#8217;t want to go out for dinner (At the moment I don&#8217;t cook myself but I&#8217;m planning to!). Next to this, these stores are 24/7 open! How べんり　(benri: convenient) is that? The prices are bit more expensive than in the supermarket, but people gladly pay a bit more for the convenience. Next to buying food, I can also withdraw cash from the ATM over there.</p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_food_establishments_at_fair_prices">Food establishments at fair prices</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<div class="paragraph">
<p>There&#8217;s no need to cook for yourself if you don&#8217;t want to. There are tons of places you can go to have lunch or dinner. Going out for food is quite common here, and therefore it doesn&#8217;t have to be expensive at all! You&#8217;d guess of course you can only get junk food at low prices but less is true. You have a lot of simple dishes that can be bought that aren&#8217;t that fat. The greatest example might be ラーメン (raamen: noodle soup) which is cheap and you feel satisfied and full after one bowl. As a person who has always struggled with his weight, I can say that I managed to keep my weight stable until now!</p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="__">百円ストアー</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<div class="paragraph">
<p>In Europe we have a similar thing, a 1 euro store, but what you often find in such stores is mostly rubbish. However in a 百円ストアー (hyaku-en stoa, 100 yen store) you find a lot of simple necessities that make your daily life easier: chopsticks, cups, glasses, plates, knifes, paper, pencils&#8230;&#8203; you find a lot of stuff at very low prices. Most of the stuff costs 100 yen (which is currently around 86 eurocents if I recall correctly), but whenever it is more expensive, it is notified on the product. However, don&#8217;t forget you pay 8% of taxes on your products, so you actually pay 108 yen for the product if it&#8217;s labeled to be 100 yen!</p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_crazy_food_combinations">Crazy food combinations</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Ever considered eating chips with honey? Or what did you think of mayonnaise on your omelet? Ketchup on your rice?! For me, it sounded really strange and disgusting, but I was wrong. Being in a new country means you will get to know new types of food and habits that you&#8217;re not used to, which is why I was really surprised by some food combinations they make in Japan, but certainly in a positive way. It&#8217;s really good! Ever considered pouring warm egg yolk (the yellow part of an egg) over your rice? You should give it a try!</p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_supermarkets_are_open_until_22_00">Supermarkets are open until 22:00</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<div class="paragraph">
<p>That&#8217;s quite late in comparison to Belgium, where the supermarkets close at 20:00 (except for 21:00 on Fridays). And you know what&#8217;s even better? The hour before they close, they give discounts to all the fresh food that&#8217;s still available and otherwise has to be thrown away! Also the supermarkets are open every day, even on Sundays! I weekly visit the supermarket before closing time to buy some milk, cereal and some other drinks in big bottles. But I also check whether there is a bento or some other dish that I can take along as late night dinner at 50% of the price.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Guess I&#8217;ll stop this post for now. Next time, I&#8217;ll try to introduce my school life in Shibuya. Hope you still enjoy my blog! Stay tuned!</p>
</div>
</div>
</div>]]></description><link>https://endymion64.github.io/2016/10/09/What-I-like-about-Japan.html</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://endymion64.github.io/2016/10/09/What-I-like-about-Japan.html</guid><pubDate>Sun, 09 Oct 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Settling in Japan]]></title><description><![CDATA[<div id="preamble">
<div class="sectionbody">
<div class="paragraph">
<p>I know it has been a while since my previous post. My apologies for my procrastination: ごめんね (gomenne: my apologies)! It&#8217;s already been a month since I touched Japanese soil for the first time, unimaginable! Time flies, it feels as if I&#8217;ve been here only 2 weeks. Anyway, I&#8217;ll finally tell some stuff that some people have been asking me for, so here we go! Let&#8217;s talk about the "struggles" I encountered in order to ensure my journey to Japan and the measures I had to take during my first days in the country in order to settle myself in the country.</p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_before_departure">Before departure</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<div class="paragraph">
<p>On the 30th of August, I left my home country to live for a whole year in Japan for the Vulcanus in Japan exchange program. Due to the duration of the program, I couldn&#8217;t simply book my flight and jump on the plane. Some paperwork had to be done before even considering booking my flight. I am obviously talking about getting a visa. As a Belgian tourist, you don&#8217;t need to do this as long as you can prove to the Japanese immigration officer at the airport that you leave Japan within 3 months, by showing your return flight ticket.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>In order to get a visa, you first of all have to get an international passport (or travel passport, whichever one sounds good for you). This is mostly acquired by queueing a long time at your town&#8217;s civil affairs department. In Belgium, you pay a minimum of €64 for a 32-page booklet, exclusive taxes. The taxes you pay depend on the city you live in. I had the luck to live in the city with the second most expensive city taxes of Belgium, hoozaah! In total, I had to pay the generous sum of €100 to get that passport set and done.
When finally acquired your passport, you&#8217;re ready to get that visa right? Well, you can sprint to the Japanese embassee in your country and apply for a visa, but the procedure will take months and the chances of being approved are low, unless you take a detour. That detour is acquiring a Certificate of Eligibility (COE for short). The COE is a document handed out by the Japanese Ministry of Foreign Affairs to approve your long visit to Japan. I won&#8217;t go into details on how you fill in the application form, but most important in order to get such a COE is having contacts in Japan.  For students, this is often the university where they will study and for employees this is often the company that hired them.　In my case, the contact was the EU-Japan Centre for Industrial Cooperation that organises the exchange program. I received my COE during the Vulcanus Preparatory Meeting in Brussels on the 7th of July.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>With your passport and COE in your hands, you&#8217;re finally ready to hop to the Japanese embasee and apply for a visa! The procedure took around a week and the result was a beautiful sticker in my passport that grants me entry to the Land of the Rising Sun, the glorious 日本 (Nihon/Nippon: Japan). The purpose of my visa mentions "cultural activities", since the exchange program I undergo is not related to an educational institute, nor am I an employee at a particular country, which means I didn&#8217;t get a student visa nor a trainee visa. I&#8217;m a mixture of both in some way.</p>
</div>
<div id="img-visa" class="imageblock">
<div class="content">
<img src="https://endymion64.github.io/images/settling/visa.jpg" alt="visa">
</div>
<div class="title">Figure 1. Look at this prety sticker, it has flowers and stuff written on it!</div>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>For my flight, I chose to leave from Schiphol, the international airport of The Netherlands. During the period I wanted to book my flight, there were regular strikes and delays at the Belgian airport due to the recent terrorist attacks. Therefore, I wanted to choose an airport with more stability. Gautier, the lone French Vulcanus trainee who had an intership in Amsterdam back then, was also planning to leave from Schiphol. Therefore we booked tickets for the same flight and reserved seats next to each other. The day of the flight was one full of nerves and excitement. I checked my luggage 3 times, just to be sure I would take everything I&#8217;d need with me! I arrived at the airport 3 hours before departure, so I could go tranquilly to my gate without any issues. The plane I was going to board was already waiting for me.</p>
</div>
<div id="img-plane" class="imageblock">
<div class="content">
<img src="https://endymion64.github.io/images/settling/plane.jpg" alt="Qatar">
</div>
<div class="title">Figure 2. This plane brought me to Qatar</div>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>First, Gautier and I flew to Qatar, where we had to transfer for our flight to Narita International Airport. In Qatar, we had to sprint since we only had an hour of transfer time and we needed to go through security checks a second time and queuing took a while. We got on time in our plane, so the real trip to Japan could start! I slept a couple of hours in this plane, so the 10-hour trip didn&#8217;t feel this long luckily! When I woke up we were already flying over China. Two hours later, we were flying over Japanese soil. With a setting sun at the horizon, I was welcomed by Mount Fuji during the landing. This was for me a sign of the start of an incredible experience!</p>
</div>
<div id="img-fuji" class="imageblock">
<div class="content">
<img src="https://endymion64.github.io/images/settling/fuji.jpg" alt="Fuji">
</div>
<div class="title">Figure 3. This is how I was welcomed into Japan</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_congratulations_you_made_it_to_japan_now_what">Congratulations, you made it to Japan! Now what?</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<div class="sect2">
<h3 id="_get_a_residence_card">Get a Residence Card</h3>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>After being landed in Narita Airport, I had to queue for passport control. During queuing I got an officer asking me the duration of my stay. The officer guided me out of the queue to some seats to wait a bit. Since I stay for more than 3 months, I had to receive a Residence Card. This card is the ID-card for foreigners who reside in Japan. This took a while and then I had a small interview with an immigration inspector and got my face photographed and fingerprints scanned, which is part of the standard procedure.</p>
</div>
<div id="img-residence" class="imageblock">
<div class="content">
<img src="https://endymion64.github.io/images/settling/residence.jpg" alt="residence">
</div>
<div class="title">Figure 4. Ooooh shinyyy</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect2">
<h3 id="_register_your_address_and_apply_for_national_health_insurance">Register your address and apply for National Health Insurance</h3>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>The first night, I stayed in a hotel together with the other Vulcanus trainees. We got our orientation day the next morning. The Japanese weather was unforgiving: a frying 34°C and a humidity level of imeasurable values. Drenched in sweat I arrived at the Europa house, where the orientation took place. After the presentation, I had to wait for a representative of Fujitsu to pick up the students that will have their internship at Fujitsu Laboratories in Kawasaki.  In total we are 3: Sašo, from Slovenia; Ole from Germany and then there&#8217;s that Belgian guy.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>The representative brought us, after a great lunch in the most Japanese place you can imagine (read: McDonald&#8217;s), to the city hall in the Nakahara ward, where we had to register the address where we will live and had to apply for National Health Insurance. I must say this was the first time I was confronted by the known fact that nobody in Japan speaks English. The documents for address registration and insurance application were completely written in Japanese, nor could anyone of the staff assist us in English. Luckily, the Fujitsu representative stayed with us the whole afternoon to complete the forms with us. The National Health Insurance is mandatory for residents that stay at least a year in Japan. Since we only stay in Japan for a bit less than a year, the staff at the city hall wasn&#8217;t convinced we were obliged to apply for the insurance, but since we had strict orders of the EU-Japan Centre, we insisted on it and received our health insurance card. After the arrangements in the city hall were done, we had a small visit to the company where we received our appartment keys and were each guided to our appartments. Normally, we were supposed to live in the dormitory of Fujitsu, but there happened to be no vacancy left, so Fujitsu booked 3 small appartments for us. The 3 of us live apart in Leopalace21 appartments. The appartments are a small 5-minute walk from each other, so we can easily hang out together. The appartment offers more benefits for us than the dorm would have done: we all have a full private accomodation now and we can invite some visitors. Bonus!!</p>
</div>
<div id="img-nhi" class="imageblock">
<div class="content">
<img src="https://endymion64.github.io/images/settling/nhi.jpg" alt="NHI">
</div>
<div class="title">Figure 5. My health insurance card, but some privacy bug removed my address ;)</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect2">
<h3 id="_get_a_bank_account">Get a bank account</h3>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>The next day, Friday the 2nd of September, the 3 Fujitsu guys went to Shibuya to get a bank account. We chose to go to Shinsei Bank, since they are one of the only banks that offer English services (as already mentioned, you easily get confronted with language barriers when it comes to particular domestic services). We went to the Shibuya office, but got kicked out. We were advised to go to the Head office near Tokyo Station, half an hour from Shibuya, because this office wasn&#8217;t familiar with dealing with a lot of foreigners at the same time. This was because there were already 2 Vulcanus trainees inside. The Head Office could handle us better&#8230;&#8203;</p>
</div>
<div class="admonitionblock warning">
<table>
<tr>
<td class="icon">
<i class="fa icon-warning" title="Warning"></i>
</td>
<td class="content">
<strong>Do not go in groups to a Japanese bank because the staff is not used to it and they will kick you out!</strong>
</td>
</tr>
</table>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>So we planned to go to the other office but had to do it the next week since we didn&#8217;t have anymore time that day, because a second orientation presentation was going to be held in the afternoon by the EU-Japan Centre and afterwards we were invited to a reception in the Sheraton Hotel where we had the honor to meet the principle and some members of the teaching staff from the Naganuma school. The ambassadors from some European countries and representatives from the different companies that participated in the Vulcanus program were also present. I had the opportunity to meet my supervisor for the internship, but the Belgian ambassador sent his regards. It was a very pleasant event nevertheless!</p>
</div>
<div id="img-bankcard" class="imageblock">
<div class="content">
<img src="https://endymion64.github.io/images/settling/bankcard.jpg" alt="Shinsei">
</div>
<div class="title">Figure 6. My cash card which allows me to withdraw money from my Japanese account, but those privacy bugs removed my account number ;)</div>
</div>
<div id="img-reception" class="imageblock">
<div class="content">
<img src="https://endymion64.github.io/images/settling/reception.jpg" alt="Reception">
</div>
<div class="title">Figure 7. This is where we held the reception, neat huh?</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect2">
<h3 id="_get_a_sim_card">Get a SIM-card</h3>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>In the first weekend, the 3 Fujitsu guys went to Shibuya again and entered a BIC CAMERA shop to get a Japanese SIM card. There are a lot of possibilities of SIM cards and plans to acquire depending on the duration of your stay and the amount of mobile data you want to consume. You can also choose whether you want a data-only SIM or would like to be able to text and make phone calls. The choice is up to you! A nice summary of the available SIM cards can be found on <a href="https://tokyocheapo.com/business/internet/prepaid-cheap-japan-sim-card-options/">Tokyo Cheapo</a> for short and long stays.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Since I stay a whole year in Japan, I chose a BIC SIM, with 3GB data per month including a phone number. Besides the initial activation costs, this will cost me 1600yen per month. Note that phone calls and text messages are excluded from this fee. So the price for the phone call you make and the numbers of texts you send will be added to this price! It is still cheap when compared to Belgium as long as you do as much as possible over mobile data which is currently possible with VOIP (Voice Over IP) and Messaging Services of Social Media.</p>
</div>
<div id="img-bic" class="imageblock">
<div class="content">
<img src="https://endymion64.github.io/images/settling/bic.jpg" alt="bic.jpg">
</div>
<div class="title">Figure 8. Sašo showing which SIMs we considered to choose</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect2">
<h3 id="_commuter_pass">Commuter pass</h3>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>From September until December, I will travel 5 days a week to the Naganuma School to learn Japanese. In order to ease my commuting with public transport, I bought a PASMO card. It&#8217;s an IC card that allows you to charge money on it which you can use to travel around using public transport including trains, metro and buses. It is a must-have if you want to travel using public transport in a comfortable way. Otherwise, you&#8217;ll have to buy tickets at a counter everytime and this can become complicated if you need to transfer onto lines that are from another company. IC cards work on all the lines. There exist several types of cards and normally it doesn&#8217;t really matter which one you buy, <strong>UNLESS</strong> you want to charge a commuter pass on it. A commuter pass is a fee you pay to travel between 2 stations on a more regular basis. Therefore, it does matter which IC card you buy, because you are obliged to travel through at least one station of the company from which you bought the IC card. Therefore I had to get a PASMO card specifically, because I can travel to the school using the Tokyu Toyoko Line, which is owned by the Tokyu Coorporation. However, in the airport I bought another IC card, Suica. This card is offered by JR, a train company. Since I do not need to travel using a JR line, I was obliged to get the other IC card. Luckily, I can get a refund on my Suica if I return it to one of the JR stations, but for now I decided to keep it since it is a pretty card with a cute penguin on it. The commuter pass is valid for a month or 3 months. For my own safety I bought a 1-month commuter passes in case I might lose my PASMO card.</p>
</div>
<div id="img-pasmo" class="imageblock">
<div class="content">
<img src="https://endymion64.github.io/images/settling/pasmo.jpg" alt="PASMO">
</div>
<div class="title">Figure 9. The very convenient PASMO card loaded with my commuter pass</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect2">
<h3 id="_get_internet_in_your_room_so_that_you_can_write_long_blog_posts">Get Internet in your room, so that you can write long blog posts</h3>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Leopalace21 provides its own Internet sevice to their appartments, which is called LEONET.
I simply had to make an account, pay for one month and all set and done: enjoy that unlimited downloading you&#8217;re used to! Only problem: the instructions were Japanese&#8230;&#8203;</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>After a couple of days trying to translate the instructions, the 3 Fujitsu guys figured out how to get stuff done and then we finally had Internet available in our appartments!
This was the final point on my bucket list to get done during the first weeks in Japan.
Now I can enjoy a comfortable life in my appartment with WiFi, travel easily to school or other destinations using public transport and get my scholarship to spend money!</p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>]]></description><link>https://endymion64.github.io/2016/10/02/Settling-in-Japan.html</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://endymion64.github.io/2016/10/02/Settling-in-Japan.html</guid><pubDate>Sun, 02 Oct 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Why I left]]></title><description><![CDATA[<div class="paragraph">
<p>After being already 10 days in Japan, I finally have found the opportunity to write my first post. We will start at the beginning, which is the reason why I left to Japan. Most of you know this already, but for the people that don&#8217;t, I&#8217;ll try to give a quick summary.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>During my first year of my Master&#8217;s program, I was already thinking about what I could do afterwards. Normally, one starts looking for a job or continues his/her studies with an additional Master&#8217;s program or PhD. I chose I could go for a PhD, since I would love to perform research in my further career and getting a PhD is in my opinion the right way to get into R&amp;D later on. However, having not that much practical experience in Computer Science, I wanted to gain some before starting a career.  That&#8217;s why I was planning to do an intern- or traineeship somewhere during summer.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>As most of you know, I am also a big fan of Japan. I love watching anime, but besides the wacko entertainment the Japanese provide, I also appreciate their ancient culture. I practice Jiu-Jitsu and I&#8217;d love to learn Kendo one day. I admire their spirit for perfectionism and their attitude to put collective harmony above personal benefit. Japan has been a source of inspiration since my childhood. That&#8217;s why I always was looking forward to visit the country one day.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Around November 2014, I received an e-mail from my faculty. It was forwarded publicity from our university&#8217;s International Relationships Office. I quickly skimmed the email and noticed it told about an international exchange program, Vulcanus, for scientists and engineers. You would get the opportunity to work in the research department of a multinational. This sounded very interesting, since I wanted to do an internship and on top of that, it concerned research. However, the fact that the internship would be international scared me a bit. Nevertheless, I read the email a second time, a bit more thoroughly and that&#8217;s when it happened. I discovered you would get a 4-month language course and afterwards start your 8-month traineeship in&#8230;&#8203; Japan.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>A whole year in the land of my dreams, gaining some practical experience in a research department and learn Japanese as a surplus. This email came like some revelation at that moment.  It combined all the topics that I was wondering about around that period. I decided to apply for this exchange program in my graduation year. This program lasts a whole year, which is why I wanted to finish my studies first. After filling in some forms, writing a CV and motivation letter, gathering documents from my university and an acknowledgement from my doctor that I&#8217;m in a proper condition to travel abroad, I had put everything together to apply for the <a href="http://www.eu-japan.eu/events/vulcanus-japan">Vulcanus in Japan</a> program, although without that much hope to succeed. It is an exchange program on European level, so I was convinced I wouldn&#8217;t be able to compete with the other applicants during the selection procedures. However, in February 2016 I got the verdict: I was selected to go to Japan. The committee that had selected me, recommended a particular traineeship at <a href="http://www.fujitsu.com/jp/group/labs/en/">Fujitsu Laboratories</a>. I had to write a motivation letter to the company and if I happened to be chosen by the company, I was ready to go.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>As you all know by now, Fujitsu Laboratories selected me for one of their internships and I am currently residing in Nakahara, Kawasaki City, in the Kanagawa prefecture, just outside of Tokyo. From September to December, I will daily commute to Shibuya, Tokyo to study Japanese at <a href="http://www.naganuma-school.ac.jp/">The Naganuma School, Tokyo School of Japanese Language</a>, together with the other 33 Vulcanus trainees. In my next post, I will talk more in detail about my flight and my first days in Japan.</p>
</div>]]></description><link>https://endymion64.github.io/2016/09/12/Why-I-left.html</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://endymion64.github.io/2016/09/12/Why-I-left.html</guid><pubDate>Mon, 12 Sep 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>