<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[Youri in Japan]]></title><description><![CDATA[My experiences in Japan during the Vulcanus in Japan 2016-2017 exchange program]]></description><link>http://youri.discovers.asia</link><generator>RSS for Node</generator><lastBuildDate>Mon, 12 Sep 2016 14:44:44 GMT</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://youri.discovers.asia/rss/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><ttl>60</ttl><item><title><![CDATA[Why I left]]></title><description><![CDATA[<div class="paragraph">
<p>After being already 10 days in Japan, I finally have found the opportunity to write my first post. We will start at the beginning, which is the reason why I left to Japan. Most of you know this already, but for the people that don&#8217;t, I&#8217;ll try to give a quick summary.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>During my first year of my Master&#8217;s program, I was already thinking about what I could do afterwards. Normally, one starts looking for a job or continues his/her studies with an additional Master&#8217;s program or PhD. I chose I could go for a PhD, since I would love to perform research in my further career and getting a PhD is in my opinion the right way to get into R&amp;D later on. However, having not that much practical experience in Computer Science, I wanted to gain some before starting a career.  That&#8217;s why I was planning to do an intern- or traineeship somewhere during summer.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>As most of you know, I am also a big fan of Japan. I love watching anime, but besides the wacko entertainment the Japanese provide, I also appreciate their ancient culture. I practice Jiu-Jitsu and I&#8217;d love to learn Kendo one day. I admire their spirit for perfectionism and their attitude to put collective harmony above personal benefit. Japan has been a source of inspiration since my childhood. That&#8217;s why I always was looking forward to visit the country one day.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Around November 2014, I received an e-mail from my faculty. It was forwarded publicity from our university&#8217;s International Relationships Office. I quickly skimmed the email and noticed it told about an international exchange program, Vulcanus, for scientists and engineers. You would get the opportunity to work in the research department of a multinational. This sounded very interesting, since I wanted to do an internship and on top of that, it concerned research. However, the fact that the internship would be international scared me a bit. Nevertheless, I read the email a second time, a bit more thoroughly and that&#8217;s when it happened. I discovered you would get a 4-month language course and afterwards start your 8-month traineeship in&#8230;&#8203; Japan.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>A whole year in the land of my dreams, gaining some practical experience in a research department and learn Japanese as a surplus. This email came like some revelation at that moment.  It combined all the topics that I was wondering about around that period. I decided to apply for this exchange program in my graduation year. This program lasts a whole year, which is why I wanted to finish my studies first. After filling in some forms, writing a CV and motivation letter, gathering documents from my university and an acknowledgement from my doctor that I&#8217;m in a proper condition to travel abroad, I had put everything together to apply for the <a href="http://www.eu-japan.eu/events/vulcanus-japan">Vulcanus in Japan</a> program, although without that much hope to succeed. It is an exchange program on European level, so I was convinced I wouldn&#8217;t be able to compete with the other applicants during the selection procedures. However, in January 2016 I got the verdict: I was selected to go to Japan. The committee that had selected me, recommended a particular traineeship at <a href="http://www.fujitsu.com/jp/group/labs/en/">Fujitsu Laboratories</a>. I had to write a motivation letter to the company and if I happened to be chosen by the company, I was ready to go.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>As you all know by now, Fujitsu Laboratories selected me for one of their internships and I am currently residing in Nakahara, Kawasaki City, in the Kanagawa prefecture, just outside of Tokyo. From September to December, I will daily commute to Shibuya, Tokyo to study Japanese at <a href="http://www.naganuma-school.ac.jp/">The Naganuma School, Tokyo School of Japanese Language</a>, together with the other 33 Vulcanus trainees. In my next post, I will talk more in detail about my flight and my first days in Japan.</p>
</div>]]></description><link>http://youri.discovers.asia/2016/09/12/Why-I-left.html</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://youri.discovers.asia/2016/09/12/Why-I-left.html</guid><pubDate>Mon, 12 Sep 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>